<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>The Ringer -  All</title>
  <updated>2020-04-20T22:33:05-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.theringer.com/rss/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T22:33:05-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T22:33:05-04:00</updated>
    <title>Breaking Down the ‘Better Call Saul’ Finale. Plus: Actor Tony Dalton on Playing Lalo Salamanca</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/QavRcbh1DoYRIzzLkXFhXqVidfc=/253x0:1520x950/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681536/MV5BNDhiMGMxNjgtN2RmMy00MTY3LWE4YWQtNDlhZjUzMWUwMTljXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyNjczOTE0MzM_._V1_SX1777_CR0_0_1777_950_AL_.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;AMC&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chris and Andy discuss the ‘Better Call Saul’ season finale, the tonal differences between ‘Breaking Bad’ and its spin-off series, and more before having a chat with Tony Dalton &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="syHbQY"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/7dPYt0ye0zlHEwf8XOtwEm" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="KfcIxH"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/7dPYt0ye0zlHEwf8XOtwEm?si=3UqvfzrMQxiBKZ1ZuDxNZg"&gt;Chris and Andy hone in on the season finale&lt;/a&gt; of their favorite show of the year: &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;. They discuss the tonal differences between the world established here and in &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, the specific performances of Bob Odenkirk and Tony Dalton, and the way the cast and crew have perfected the craft of the &lt;em&gt;Breaking&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Bad&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; extended universe (1:02). Then, Dalton joins the show to discuss his role as Lalo Salamanca, what he takes from the page and makes his own, and the most rewarding aspects of working in a high-level ensemble cast (44:32).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nvgVKA"&gt;Hosts: Chris Ryan and Andy Greenwald&lt;br&gt;Guest: Tony Dalton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bZKwE3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/3IcA76e8ZV0NNSJ81XHQUg?si=y_oT-MnKSR-KxdRTokKqMw"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/the-watch/id1111739567?mt=2"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://art19.com/shows/the-watch"&gt;Art19&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-ringer/the-watch"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/rss/the-watch/index.xml"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4wJqr"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21229034/breaking-down-the-better-call-saul-finale-plus-actor-tony-dalton-on-playing-lalo-salamanca"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21229034/breaking-down-the-better-call-saul-finale-plus-actor-tony-dalton-on-playing-lalo-salamanca</id>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Ryan</name>
      <name>Andy Greenwald</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T22:30:54-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T22:30:54-04:00</updated>
    <title>Kim Wexler Is the ‘Better Call Saul’ MVP </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MttESwGLgJ3zu087gMqMdGYKSJA=/240x0:1680x1080/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681530/Wexler_Thumb2_v7_TEXTLESS.0.jpg" /&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;After an explosive Season 5 finale, ‘Better Call Saul’ has left us with many questions heading into the final season—namely, what will happen to Kim Wexler? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="0Z1cSU"&gt;After an explosive Season 5 finale, &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; has left us with many questions heading into the final season. Including: What makes Jimmy McGill go FULL SAUL GOODMAN? Does Nacho survive working for both Gus Fring and Lalo Salamanca? And what does Mike Ehrmantraut do to protect the ones he loves? But as the bridge closes between &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, there’s one question on everyone’s mind. What happens to Kim Wexler?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JGPMfS"&gt;Jackson Maher dives deep into the Emmy-worthy performance of Rhea Seehorn and what makes Kim Wexler the &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; MVP.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/video/2020/4/20/21228883/kim-wexler-is-the-better-call-saul-mvp"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/video/2020/4/20/21228883/kim-wexler-is-the-better-call-saul-mvp</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jackson Maher</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T22:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T22:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Nobody Is Immune to Breaking Bad on ‘Better Call Saul’</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/guD5lkuDy2zZRn-3SB7xDEwtg-g=/167x0:2834x2000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681517/miles_sau_finale_amc_ringer.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;AMC/Ringer illustration&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In the Season 5 finale, Kim Wexler proves to be her own worst enemy, and everybody inches closer toward doom&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="IWHOTY"&gt;“Am I bad for you?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VUACIU"&gt;It’s taken the better part of &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;’s five seasons, but Jimmy McGill is finally saying the quiet part out loud: that his slide into becoming Saul Goodman has induced moral rot within Kim Wexler. It isn’t much of a consolation for Jimmy to understand the full consequences of his actions in the Season 5 finale, “Something Unforgivable,” not when the realization required a &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/6/21210334/better-call-saul-season-five-episode-eight"&gt;near-death experience in the desert&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/13/21219265/better-call-saul-season-5-episode-9-recap"&gt;terrifying confrontation&lt;/a&gt; with Lalo Salamanca under the pretext of him becoming a friend of the cartel. “You crossed a line,” Kim says to her—it’s still weird to type this out—husband. “You’re not gonna do it again.” But any viewer vaguely familiar with the events of &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt; understands that isn’t true, and it’s hard to imagine Kim truly believes what she’s saying, either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nXvpGy"&gt;Following the intense, pulse-pounding thrills of the last two episodes, when &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul &lt;/em&gt;was operating closer to a peak &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt; wavelength than its usual understated vibe, Jimmy and Kim fall back down to Earth in Monday night’s finale. (That isn’t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; the case with Lalo and Nacho Varga, whose half of the episode delivers more cartel violence that’s all the more exciting for how both characters’ fates remain uncertain; protect Nacho’s wholesome dad at all costs.) But “Something Unforgivable” chips away at the ethical boundaries the characters are willing to cross—and the scariest part is Jimmy ends the penultimate season seeming like the voice of reason. It appears Kim may fully break bad before Saul. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;div id="uu7rI8"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/t9bNWCirA1s?rel=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media; accelerometer; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="eoFnrC"&gt;After Lalo leaves Kim’s apartment at the end of last week’s episode, she and Jimmy elect to spend the night at a nice hotel. (Jimmy believes it is safer than a dinky motel because there are more people around.) He can’t entirely ensure their safety since Mike Ehrmantraut doesn’t disclose why, exactly, they wouldn’t have to worry about Lalo anymore—as much as Jimmy hopes Kim will just stay at the hotel and luxuriate in the fancy amenities, she isn’t going to put her life on hold indefinitely. She returns to the courthouse the next morning and begins taking more overflow cases from the public defender’s office—now that she’s quit &lt;a href="https://breakingbad.fandom.com/wiki/Schweikart_and_Cokely"&gt;Schweikart and Cokely&lt;/a&gt; and her work with Mesa Verde, she can handle pro bono clients on a full-time basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nrRwS4"&gt;It’s a decision that, while well-intentioned, does seem irrational and impulsive: Pro bono work is great and all, but how exactly will Kim pay the bills? It’s clearly something that she hasn’t really considered. After learning that Kim quit her job in a chance meeting in one of the courthouse elevators, Howard Hamlin confronts her. He thinks that Kim’s behavior might have something to do with Jimmy, and so Howard brings her up to speed. He explains what Jimmy did after Howard offered him a job at HHM: throwing bowling balls at his Jaguar, hiring prostitutes to embarrass him at a work lunch, and all but confessing to it in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y_E1E9tm7hs"&gt;Bob Odenkirk’s Emmy-worthy tirade&lt;/a&gt; at the end of the seventh episode.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j7XWPH"&gt;“That’s it?” Kim says after cackling. “Howard, you really had me going there.” Jimmy’s antics might feel trivial compared to his almost dying while collecting $7 million in bail money for a drug kingpin, but let’s face it, Howard is right. This is not normal behavior, and neither was Kim’s when she brushed this revelation off like it was a funny prank. (In the past two seasons, Patrick Fabian has been excellent in small doses, turning Howard from an unlikable avatar of wealthy private law into a genuinely sympathetic figure.) But Howard suggests that Jimmy is the one responsible for Kim’s erratic actions as if she doesn’t have any agency, which sets her off. “Do you have any idea how insulting that is?” Kim says, at which point I thought we’d be in store for a retread of when she &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gJOl5OnH9oI"&gt;ethered Howard in Season 4&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="EL1BuX"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/7dPYt0ye0zlHEwf8XOtwEm" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="3aKSQh"&gt;&lt;br&gt;Instead, after reconvening with Jimmy at the hotel for a room service dinner, she lays out what happened, mocking Howard for claiming to have her best interests in mind. It’s hard for the viewer to stomach, but the tragic irony is that Jimmy doesn’t appear to like what he’s seeing in Kim either—a reflection of his own worst behavior. Kim starts brainstorming ways to get back at Howard, settling on drugging him(!) and shaving his head in his sleep. “Nair,” Jimmy responds, reluctantly and without any of his trademark enthusiasm for petty scheming. Sneaking the hair removal product into his shampoo bottle would be a subtler way to get the job done. Even though Jimmy’s heart isn’t in it, all this talk of screwing over Howard is a prelude to sex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="d8nnUA"&gt;Unfortunately, Kim only begins thinking bigger—and more criminal. She wants to get Howard into serious trouble—misconduct, misappropriating funds, witness tampering—with an eye toward Jimmy receiving a cushy financial settlement from the &lt;a href="https://breakingbad.fandom.com/wiki/Sandpiper_Crossing,_Albuquerque"&gt;Sandpiper Crossing&lt;/a&gt; retirement home case. Howard absolutely doesn’t deserve this kind of payback; this is leagues removed from Jimmy and Kim conning a rich dude out of an &lt;a href="https://breakingbad.fandom.com/wiki/Zafiro_A%C3%B1ejo"&gt;expensive bottle of tequila&lt;/a&gt;. “Kim, doing this, it’s not you,” Jimmy says, again lighting a fuse by trying to tell her what she is and isn’t capable of. “You would not be OK with it. Not in the cold light of day.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="ergrrw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"In Season 5, the Two Sides of ‘Better Call Saul’ Became One","url":"https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/20/21227390/better-call-saul-season-5-review-jimmy-mcgill-kim-wexler"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="ddyiWv"&gt;“Wouldn’t I?” she responds, a faint grin spreading across her face. The implications are a lot more subtle than when Walter White watched Jane Margolis slowly choke to death on her own vomit without intervening, but what Kim portends to accomplish would be a similar point of no return. In a clever, devastating callback to the &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2018/10/9/17953970/three-takeaways-better-call-saul-season-4"&gt;Season 4 finale&lt;/a&gt;—when Kim, horrified at the depths to which Jimmy plunged to be reinstated as a lawyer, was given shallow reassurance in the form of Jimmy &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Rj5g4gBlso"&gt;pointing his fingers and saying his trademark “s’all good, man”&lt;/a&gt;—she pulls out the finger guns. &lt;em&gt;Pew pew.&lt;/em&gt; The genius of “Something Unforgivable” is that it zigged where we assumed the finale would zag: Instead of Jimmy doubling down on his worst impulses, we’ve seen them manifest within Kim. Did Jimmy help create a monster? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H6ezmh"&gt;Yes and no. The clever, nuanced character work and &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/2/21/21146275/better-call-saul-season-5-breaking-bad-legacy"&gt;slow-burn nature of &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;rewards us here, making Kim’s possible heel turn less of a plot contrivance and more of a natural extension of her strong, unshakable convictions. As we learned from a flashback to her childhood at the start of this season’s sixth episode, Kim’s always been intensely stubborn and principled. When her mother picks her up &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; late from school after drinking, Kim disapproves. The moral imperative is obvious: drinking and driving is dangerous. But rather than simply chastise her mom, Kim literally refuses to get in the car—choosing to walk 3 miles back to her house in the middle of the night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GzzLig"&gt;It’s an instructive scene that helps explain why Kim has repeatedly ignored all warning signs with Jimmy. Having already convinced herself that the good of Jimmy outweighs the bad, she will hold that conviction to its breaking point. We’re well past the point of logic, and in the moral universe of &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;—a series in which, lest we forget, she never shows up—the cost of Kim’s inevitable reckoning could be steep. It’s a fool’s errand to predict what will happen in the remainder of &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;, but if I had to guess, I’d say Kim is headed for incarceration if she tries to pull off this scam against Howard in the sixth and final season. Saul Goodman might be sleazy and obsequious, but his behavior in &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;—i.e., calling his assistant Francesca “honey tits”— wouldn’t make tonal sense after the love of his life was killed, as so many fans have long feared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b52VhA"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul &lt;/em&gt;is rarely, if ever, a feel-good show—and Kim’s turn is a hell of a gut punch to sit on between seasons. (As is Lalo surviving his assassination attempt and realizing that Nacho was working for Gus Fring this entire time.) But it’s also thrilling to see how the prequel series has evolved and sharpened some of the key ingredients from &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;. As critic and frequent &lt;em&gt;Ringer&lt;/em&gt; contributor &lt;a href="https://cinema-scope.com/features/power-attorney-better-call-saul/"&gt;Adam Nayman astutely pointed out after&lt;em&gt; Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;’s second season concluded&lt;/a&gt;, the bitter feud between Jimmy and Chuck McGill had biblical, Cain-and-Abel undertones—a charge that carried the series through the first three seasons until Chuck’s suicide. Jimmy and Chuck’s sibling rivalry was essential to making the show stand on its own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="os4UTV"&gt;And while Chuck still looms heavy over &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; in death—an invisible force that seems to judge and taunt Jimmy enough that he aspires to be, as he told Howard, a “god in human clothing”—the closer the show inches toward &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, the more it becomes a different study in duality. The through line for characters in this universe is that anybody trying to maintain this sort of dualistic lifestyle is bound to fall apart—there was only so long that Walter White could juggle being a terminally ill family man and Heisenberg; being a fast food magnate and a meth kingpin &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MybaTnzu9AA"&gt;blew up in Gus Fring’s face&lt;/a&gt;. On &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;, we’re seeing the impossibility of being both Jimmy McGill and Saul Goodman; Mike the doting grandfather is slowly giving way to Mike the efficient cartel henchman; Nacho’s existence as a reluctant double agent has finally been exposed. This idea also extends to the &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/20/21227390/better-call-saul-season-5-review-jimmy-mcgill-kim-wexler"&gt;storytelling this season&lt;/a&gt;, as the walls between the legal and gangland halves of the series have crumbled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qC24S0"&gt;As for Kim, how long can she maintain the duality of a pro bono lawyer helping out the little guy and someone willing to destroy an innocent man’s career for a multimillion dollar payday? Time and again, the characters in this universe have been cautionary tales about the unstable nature of duality, and the ethical compromises required of it. Even when Jimmy takes on a third identity in &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;’s post–&lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt; flash-forwards as &lt;a href="https://breakingbad.fandom.com/wiki/Cinnabon,_Omaha"&gt;Gene Takovic the Cinnabon manager&lt;/a&gt;, he’s exposed for his sins as Saul Goodman by a man who recognizes him from his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wqnHtGgVAUE"&gt;commercials&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Xr7Q6P"&gt;But if Jimmy isn’t deserving of redemption like &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2019/10/11/20909943/el-camino-breaking-bad-jesse-pinkman-netflix"&gt;Jesse Pinkman through the events of &lt;em&gt;El Camino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, he may yet be entitled to some emotional closure. While Kim’s &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul &lt;/em&gt;fate hangs in the balance, it’s worth noting that Jimmy chose Omaha, Nebraska, for his new lease on life. Though ending up in Nebraska and managing a Cinnabon was itself the result of a throwaway line from Saul at the end of&lt;em&gt; Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; has seemingly taken the detail to heart: Kim’s mother had a Nebraska license plate in that aforementioned flashback. This has led some fans to believe &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; will end with Jimmy and Kim reuniting at, of all places, a goddamn Cinnabon—and even if it isn’t under the happiest of circumstances, at least they’d be alive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OucErC"&gt;It’s an interesting proposition, but on a series that’s been shockingly unpredictable for a prequel and extremely effective at navigating its way out of narrative corners, I’ll be surprised if &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul &lt;/em&gt;chooses the path many expect them to. And if cocreators Peter Gould and Vince Gilligan actually &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; go this route, it would likely still be a sensible and emotional coda—not something akin to Bran Stark becoming the ruler of the Seven Kingdoms. In fact, unless &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;’s final season is a complete misfire that draws unsavory comparisons to what transpired in Westeros—something that, given the bonafides of everyone involved on the show, feels as unlikely as Mike Ehrmantraut deciding to spend the rest of the series wearing a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TomSchnauz/status/1250160475389562880"&gt;Land of Enchantment T-shirt and basketball shorts&lt;/a&gt;—the real conversation might harken back to just where this series belongs in the annals of great television. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v6SRKJ"&gt;The fifth season of &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul &lt;/em&gt;was a bleak, beautiful masterpiece: a triumph on the levels of writing, performance, cinematography, direction, and, of course, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GnEQJsJOJP8"&gt;dank montages&lt;/a&gt;. This was always a great, if somewhat underappreciated show, but there’s never been a better time to say the other quiet part out loud: &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; has surpassed&lt;em&gt; Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;. The show has taken the composite parts of a highly regarded series and excelled on its own terms. It has made the slow devolution of Jimmy into Saul crushing in its inevitability. It has turned Kim Wexler into not just a character worthy of the &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt; universe hall of fame, but someone who belongs in the discussion for all-time great TV characters. For my editor’s sake, don’t even get me started on the lack of Emmy nominations for Rhea Seehorn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="uQaGHA"&gt;A series operating at this level for a sustained period of time is its own form of alchemy—something as pure as Heisenberg’s &lt;a href="https://breakingbad.fandom.com/wiki/Blue_Sky"&gt;Blue Sky&lt;/a&gt; and stunning as a New Mexico desert vista. Really, what more I can say? &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt; is just so good, man. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2Q7gbo"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"ringer_newsletter"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/20/21228206/better-call-saul-season-5-finale"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/tv/2020/4/20/21228206/better-call-saul-season-5-finale</id>
    <author>
      <name>Miles Surrey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T22:03:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T22:03:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>’Listen to Your Heart’ Episode 2, Catfishing Reality Steve, and Quarantine Couples Victoria F. and Chris Soules and Peter and Kelley</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SQHxOCULkmeaVy7A53dV-ogwocg=/206x0:2873x2000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681493/154812_4346.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;ABC&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Juliet is joined by Lauren Zima to discuss the second episode of ‘The Bachelor Presents: Listen to Your Heart,’ quarantine couples in Bachelor Nation, and more&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="sUN95c"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/7rgHd7deKaQqwUUjsoM5hg" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="nmo3Nb"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7AfEmlLWtCW1dngO9sCJYm?si=qb1hSy7dQnyVcRBSKWO2QA"&gt;Juliet is joined by Lauren Zima&lt;/a&gt; to chat about all of the quarantine couples in Bachelor Nation, including Victoria F. and former Bachelor Chris Soules (9:00), before getting into the bizarre news of Reality Steve getting catfished about the Jenna Cooper and Jordan Kimball cheating scandal from years back (16:00). Finally, we break down the second episode of &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor Presents: Listen to Your Heart&lt;/em&gt; and why this show works (19:50).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sl4rPE"&gt;Host: Juliet Litman&lt;br&gt;Guest: Lauren Zima&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wa8bxk"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7AfEmlLWtCW1dngO9sCJYm?si=Y-tkJNu2ROSCX8YcOi5Z3g"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/id1330224581"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://art19.com/shows/bachelor-party"&gt;Art19&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=162330&amp;amp;refid=stpr"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/BachelorParty"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228940/listen-to-your-heart-episode-2-catfish-reality-steve-quarantine-couples-victoria-chris-peter-kelley"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228940/listen-to-your-heart-episode-2-catfish-reality-steve-quarantine-couples-victoria-chris-peter-kelley</id>
    <author>
      <name>Juliet Litman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T22:02:17-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T22:02:17-04:00</updated>
    <title>Listen to Your Heart’ Recap: The Laws of Emotional Cheating</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Pwau8aI4ZmO-5Y4Xn4KJ95LpA7M=/65x0:1132x800/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681487/LTYHEp2_ABC_Getty_Ringer.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Getty Images/ABC/Ringer illustration&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you think about it, we’re all emotionally cheating on ‘The Bachelorette’ with ‘Listen to Your Heart’&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="cLOpUC"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bachelor Presents: Listen to Your Heart&lt;/em&gt; is based on the premise that it’s possible to simultaneously find a soulmate and musical partner. (Actual evidence of this theory from the world of music seems to be lacking, but I have listened to &lt;em&gt;Rumours&lt;/em&gt; a lot more since making a Fleetwood Mac joke in &lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/13/21219841/listen-to-your-heart-premiere-recap-the-bachelor-singing-show"&gt;my last recap&lt;/a&gt;.) Each episode repeatedly shows coupled-up contestants performing together. And after two episodes, I have one big question: What happens if the show’s breakout couple sucks at singing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="ofj4uj"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://art19.com/shows/bachelor-party/episodes/0806fae5-64f0-45dc-8be1-8b1956b1de09/embed?theme=light-gray-blue" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 200px;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f4ehR6"&gt;Much of the plot of the first two episodes has centered around Trevor, a former &lt;em&gt;American Idol&lt;/em&gt; contestant who &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6a-1dMYKVQY"&gt;was openly lusted after by Katy Perry on air,&lt;/a&gt; and Jamie, a 21-year-old fresh out of Berklee trying to make a name for herself in the music industry and on Instagram. (It doesn’t seem like &lt;em&gt;Listen to Your Heart&lt;/em&gt; carries the IG pull a typical season of &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; does—after one episode, &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/jamiegabriellemusic/?hl=en"&gt;Jamie still hasn’t cracked 20,000 followers&lt;/a&gt;.) In the first episode, clean-shaven Ryan made a strong play for Jamie, but after a John Mayer song duel, she chose Trevor. On Monday night’s episode, Jamie and Trevor got the first date, but their relationship was nearly derailed by the entrance of Natascha, who claimed to know Trevor’s ex and warned Jamie about Trevor’s history of cheating-adjacent behavior. (We’ll get into this later.) That’s how you know Jamie and Trevor are going far on this show—the producers are bringing in people from their pasts to stir up drama. They don’t waste that kind of effort on nobodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2EKXsx"&gt;But there’s something much more pressing that’s keeping Jamie and Trevor from being the show’s runaway favorites. Here is what it sounds like when they sing together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="NeoowI"&gt;&lt;div style="left: 0; width: 100%; height: 0; position: relative; padding-bottom: 55.8685%;"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/409949921?byline=0&amp;amp;badge=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;title=0" style="border: 0; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="phHzxt"&gt;As Jamie and Trevor busked on Venice Beach, I kept thinking: Would I stop if I was walking down the promenade and heard these two voices? The answer is a resounding no. And yet, the show insults us by implying that dozens of people &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; stop and listen. We’re even shown passersby dropping money in their guitar case—at the end of the date, Jamie claims they collected $82, apparently from playing a single song. I’d be surprised to hear that a high-quality singer got $82 in an hour of boardwalk singing—and these guys got that much from &lt;em&gt;one song?&lt;/em&gt; (Did Jamie and Trevor get to keep the money, or did &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt;, which airs on ABC, which is owned by Disney, end up pocketing these donations from beachgoers?) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UFaBTJ"&gt;I’m not here just to cynically dump on this show. On Monday night’s episode, four couples performed together, and honestly, three of them sounded great. I really cannot stress enough that only Jamie and Trevor sound bad. Jamie’s been pitchy on both of her performances, and Trevor doesn’t sound too much different from any frat guy with a guitar. It feels like the show has 14 professional musicians and two people hot enough that everybody humors their attempts to sing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="42AdTD"&gt;Does this matter? It’s unclear. The show claims that in the end, performers will be judged on their musical &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; romantic compatibility, but we haven’t yet seen the grading rubric in action. I guess it’s possible for someone to win by scoring a 100 on “hotness” and a zero on “singing.” That’s Jamie and Trevor’s only hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ywTdZn"&gt;Hottest Buzzword: “Emotional Cheating” &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kGiZNx"&gt;Natascha wastes no time before attempting to defame Trevor. Basically, she enters the house, hears that a contestant is named “Trevor,” and instantly screams “You mean &lt;em&gt;TREVOR FROM AMERICAN IDOL?&lt;/em&gt;” A pretty bold guess by her, considering how many Trevors there must be in the world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xi1CrA"&gt;Despite Natascha’s instant realization that “Trevor” was a guy she knew, Trevor enters and seems to have no idea who Natascha is. She fills him in: Natascha knows Trevor’s ex-girlfriend—the one whom Katy Perry seemed to wish dead on &lt;em&gt;American Idol&lt;/em&gt;—and is aware that he cheated on her and lied to her. Trevor responds by claiming he didn’t actually cheat on his ex, but did participate in “emotional cheating”—as he explains it, he carried on a text relationship with another woman as his relationship with his ex soured. Natascha, meanwhile, continues to rip into Trevor about how he didn’t inform Jamie that he cheated on his ex. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GEkW0Q"&gt;Natascha, it should be noted, is a habitual Fringe Reality TV Singing Competition Contestant. She’s been on the Dutch version of &lt;em&gt;The Voice&lt;/em&gt;, attempted to become the Dutch representative to the Eurovision Song Contest, and—this is the most important one—was on the 2007 show &lt;em&gt;The Pussycat Dolls Present: The Search for the Next Doll&lt;/em&gt;. She did not become the next Pussycat Doll, presumably because viewers did not &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YNSxNsr4wmA"&gt;wish that their girlfriends were hot like her&lt;/a&gt;. She’s a pro. And when the show’s producers contacted her and told her to pick a fight with Trevor, she knew she had to give 110 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a8DNKM"&gt;Unfortunately, she’s a bit &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; vigorous. I don’t quite buy her righteous rage in an attempt to burn a guy she barely knows, nor her repeated insistence that she wants to protect Jamie, whom she hasn’t even met yet. And, not to defend cheaters, but is it considered mandatory for cheaters to confess all instances of past cheating on first dates? Seems abrupt, especially if the cheating in question was more figurative than literal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oObt1n"&gt;Even though Natascha’s attempts at gotcha journalism seem forced, Trevor decides he’s gonna run with the “emotional cheating” thing. He actually pulls Jamie aside and admits to her that he emotionally cheated on his ex-girlfriend. Which, like, if all you did was text someone else, &lt;em&gt;why would you ever agree to use the word “cheating” when describing it to your new girlfriend?&lt;/em&gt; Trevor’s gotta be covering for actual cheating, right? Because otherwise, just say you texted somebody, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R2Aso9"&gt;All of this comes to nothing. Jamie doesn’t seem too bothered by Trevor’s emotional cheating, and Natascha’s efforts at spoiling their relationship are dashed. But we can’t say Natascha didn’t warn us if Trevor commits “spiritual adultery” or “psychological fornication” somewhere down the line. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="h0dMEz"&gt;Biggest Trend: Cheap Dates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="OauGwH"&gt;One way &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor &lt;/em&gt;tricks contestants into thinking they may be falling in love is by sending them on very nice dates. It’s probably much easier to be convinced there’s a real spark between you and someone with whom you share no common interests if you’ve been flown to a secluded mountain waterfall by a helicopter. For example, on a typical &lt;em&gt;Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; date from this past season, Peter and Victoria flew to a theme park that was entirely closed so they could go on all the rides by themselves, and then country star Chase Rice put on a one-song concert just for them. I don’t know anybody with the money or the connections to shut down a theme park &lt;em&gt;or &lt;/em&gt;convince a well-known country musician to fly in to perform exactly one song. I, for one, would immediately fall in love with someone if they deprived hundreds of children of a fun day at an amusement park just for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X0lcXs"&gt;But while &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; can afford to put a lot of money and effort into its one-on-one dates—because it’s one of the most popular shows on television—&lt;em&gt;Listen to Your Heart &lt;/em&gt;has no such budgetary freedom. So instead of waterfalls and shopping sprees, &lt;em&gt;L2YH &lt;/em&gt;gets this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="TPawp3"&gt;A trip to Venice Beach, where Trevor and Jamie play a song on the boardwalk for passersby. &lt;strong&gt;Cost: &lt;/strong&gt;$0, unless they had to pay to install that random hot tub. Plus, as we have already discussed, the show may have &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; money off of this date. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="eAuO7x"&gt;A trip to an empty Guitar Center for Bri and Chris to play around with the instruments. However, this is not just any Guitar Center—Chris makes sure to clarify that they’re in “&lt;em&gt;THE MOST ICONIC GUITAR CENTER.&lt;/em&gt;” All joking aside, it’s a pretty good date idea by the show—anybody who plays music has probably gone into a Guitar Center at least once to just play random instruments without purchasing anything. Though it is a bit awkward because Bri doesn’t seem to actually play any instruments. &lt;strong&gt;Cost: &lt;/strong&gt;Probably $0—the date was filmed at night, presumably after Guitar Center’s regular business hours, and it’s safe to assume Guitar Center was more than happy to open the doors of its most iconic location for the tradeoff of being featured on the show. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="3Xup9a"&gt;A visit to a radio studio, where the hosts of a show called “Valentine in the Morning” ask Sheridan and Julia a few questions before coaxing them into performing a song together. This is the date that comes closest to a typical &lt;em&gt;Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; date—they had to inconvenience some minor celebrities! (For the record, it does not appear as if Sheridan and Julia’s performance was actually broadcast on the radio as promised during the episode. I’m holding out to see whether it’s a “&lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/02/05/business/cosmopolitan-bachelor-victoria-fuller-cover-trnd/index.html"&gt;Victoria didn’t get her promised &lt;em&gt;Cosmo&lt;/em&gt; cover because she modeled in racism-adjacent clothing&lt;/a&gt;” situation.) &lt;strong&gt;Cost: &lt;/strong&gt;$0 again, unless you count the gas money spent to drive the couple from the mansion to the station. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="jmBP0G"&gt;Brandon and Savannah’s trip to the Dresden, a historic lounge where they sing some jazz together and meet Marty and Elayne, the couple who have been performing there since the 1970s. This date is less about how frugal &lt;em&gt;Listen to Your Heart &lt;/em&gt;has been with its dates and more about showing how creative the show has had to get. On the one hand, the Dresden is a legit L.A. institution. (It was in &lt;em&gt;Swingers&lt;/em&gt;!) On the other hand, as a Los Feliz resident, it is &lt;em&gt;stunning&lt;/em&gt; that &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; decided to film a date here. Normally the show sticks to downtown L.A. or Hollywood; if they’ve got camerapeople dodging hipsters, you &lt;em&gt;know &lt;/em&gt;they’re desperate for content. If &lt;em&gt;The Bachelor&lt;/em&gt; shows up to film while I try to eat wings at Ye Rustic Inn, I’m gonna fight somebody. &lt;strong&gt;Cost: &lt;/strong&gt;Roughly $100 (depending on how many cocktails Brandon and Savannah had).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3cNRDV"&gt;Best Moment: Trying to Win Over the Last Single Guy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="u4g2AX"&gt;Much like &lt;em&gt;Bachelor in Paradise&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; L2YH &lt;/em&gt;repeatedly, drastically shifts the flow of the show by introducing large swaths of new contestants. On the show’s first week, there were 12 men and eight women, leading to the elimination of four men at the end of the episode. But last night, there were 11 women and eight men, leading to the elimination of three women. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zYrSS9"&gt;This drives the action of the show by forcing extraneous, uncoupled contestants to fight for survival. In Monday night’s episode, the attempts to stay on the show were particularly desperate—and, therefore, enjoyable to watch. The Last Single Guy this time around was Ryan, the contestant who may or may not be capable of growing facial hair. (There’s another contestant without facial hair, Brandon, but I think he has to shave.) Ryan’s had a bad run—in the first episode, he competed for Jamie but lost, and needed to be saved at the last moment. It kind of seems like nobody likes him!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yxuEqV"&gt;But because there were more women than men, the ones without partners lined up to smooch Ryan’s smooth face. First up was Natascha, whose attempts at selling her passion for Ryan were about as convincing as her attempts at selling her disgust with Trevor earlier. “You give me a vibe of a Clark Kent–esque situation,” she says. Ryan is confused, because Natascha is dressed like a person who likes partying at clubs and Ryan is dressed like a person who got picked on in high school by the people who partied at clubs. But she’s into that, she unconvincingly explains. “I kinda like the nerdy type. I’m most attracted to that, because I find that sexy.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TWWZS3"&gt;Do you remember the song “This Is Why I’m Hot” by Mims, in which Mims purportedly sets out to explain why he’s hot but never actually does (besides when he says he’s hot “because I’m fly, and you ain’t because you not”)? When you break it down, this is essentially Natascha’s explanation. She is most attracted to the nerdy type because she finds it sexy. She doesn’t say &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; she finds it sexy or give any evidence that she is attracted to other nerdy-type men, besides a comic book character who is also stronger and faster than any human to ever live. One could argue that the nature of physical attraction is unexplainable, but I’d also like to point out that Mims’s inability to explain his own hotness immediately prefaced his complete and utter disappearance from rap, which shows that you probably should be able to explain hotness. In the end, it doesn’t matter: Natascha just starts making out with Ryan immediately after failing to explain his hotness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByR3qf"&gt;Next comes Rudi, who’s armed with another, less flattering comparison to a fictional character. “You look like a very cute Harry Potter,” she says. Then, after a few moments of giggling, she blurts out “we should kiss right now,” and starts vigorously making out with Ryan. (I mean, who isn’t turned on by the thought of a 14-year-old British wizard?) But much like how Cho Chang’s kiss with Harry instantly made her think of Cedric Diggory, Rudi’s kiss with Ryan instantly makes her realize she has no connection with him. “I felt nothing,” she tells another contestant, before returning to Matt, her fling from the previous episode. (I guess the Plain White T’s incident from last week didn’t hurt Rudi’s feelings too badly.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="ZShhVN"&gt;In the end, Ryan picks Natascha. She will assuredly dump him next week when the numbers switch again and she’s put in a position of power. I just hope Ryan enjoyed his one night of being the hottest commodity on the make-out/music TV show. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228727/listen-to-your-heart-episode-2-recap-jamie-trevor"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228727/listen-to-your-heart-episode-2-recap-jamie-trevor</id>
    <author>
      <name>Rodger Sherman</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T20:17:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T20:17:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>‘Ferris Bueller’s Day Off’ With Bill Simmons, Sean Fennessey, and Chris Ryan</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/J04w1q2Po23zKtDFghl5AO4zPF8=/114x0:1447x1000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681306/MV5BMTgxMTk5OTgyOF5BMl5BanBnXkFtZTcwMjI0OTI2OQ__._V1_SY1000_CR0_0_1487_1000_AL_.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Paramount Pictures&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Stay home and rewatch this 1986 classic starring Matthew Broderick, Alan Ruck, and Mia Sara&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="Lw1ipT"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/show/1lUPomulZRPquVAOOd56EW" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="OD0GC2"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ringer&lt;/em&gt;’s Bill Simmons, Sean Fennessey, and Chris Ryan aren’t feeling too well, so their parents let them stay home to rewatch the 1986 classic &lt;em&gt;Ferris Bueller’s Day Off&lt;/em&gt;, starring Matthew Broderick, Alan Ruck, and Mia Sara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C3QJOU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/1lUPomulZRPquVAOOd56EW?si=CXNVcAE7Rt6RkFEiGgod3g"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com/?id=&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fpodcast%2Fthe-rewatchables%2Fid1268527882%3Fmt%3D2&amp;amp;xcust=xid:fr1570813352074dcc%7Cxid:fr1571114040343jgb"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://art19.com/shows/the-rewatchables"&gt;Art19&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-ringer/the-rewatchables"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/therewatchables"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228570/ferris-buellers-day-off-with-bill-simmons-sean-fennessey-and-chris-ryan"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228570/ferris-buellers-day-off-with-bill-simmons-sean-fennessey-and-chris-ryan</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bill Simmons</name>
      <name>Sean Fennessey</name>
      <name>Chris Ryan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T19:58:31-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T19:58:31-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Official Burrow vs. Tua Debate</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="LSU v Alabama" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/MfvWtDDOphb-6ciwz6cUjNZ1HnA=/0x0:3796x2847/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681242/1186608460.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Photo by Kevin C. Cox/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Kevin and Danny Kelly break down every aspect of the Joe Burrow vs. Tua Tagovailoa discussion, including the most NFL-translatable qualities each QB possesses&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="Ssf7Cf"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/3D0rjSaJs17vUrazCx12N6" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hAXatQ"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/3D0rjSaJs17vUrazCx12N6?si=mNB7BMxVRe6y9cEnFKgiNw"&gt;Kevin Clark is joined by Danny Kelly&lt;/a&gt; to break down every aspect of the Joe Burrow vs. Tua Tagovailoa discussion, including the most NFL-translatable qualities each QB possesses, whether Tua would be drafted ahead of Burrow if he had never gotten hurt, Burrow’s legendary competitiveness, where Tua should land, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3BLFv4"&gt;Host: Kevin Clark&lt;br&gt;Guest: Danny Kelly&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228896/the-official-burrow-vs-tua-debate"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228896/the-official-burrow-vs-tua-debate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Clark</name>
      <name>Danny Kelly</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T19:41:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T19:41:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Jordan Doc, the Death of the Indie Bookstore, and More </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="Michael Jordan looks to rebound" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/WTChvTqU9s3lXV4Gk8CMPgyO058=/0x781:3840x3661/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681204/1965605.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Photo by Nathaniel S. Butler/NBAE via Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Plus, an update on media companies hit hard by the pandemic&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div id="itVcuz"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed-podcast/episode/5s8GHkCSrTiJvS55HAqVc1" style="border: 0; width: 100%; height: 232px;" allowfullscreen="" allow="encrypted-media"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="joq6of"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/episode/5s8GHkCSrTiJvS55HAqVc1"&gt;Bryan Curtis and David Shoemaker discuss&lt;/a&gt; their first impressions of the Michael Jordan documentary &lt;em&gt;The Last Dance&lt;/em&gt; (1:40). They then go over the Overworked Twitter Joke of the Week (35:20), the death of the beloved indie bookstore (38:05), and more from the Hall of Shame, with updates on media companies hit hard by the pandemic (48:32).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U4govp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribe:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/4aBkZbDqL5q44JPnmNj6Hq?si=sbC9UQpORXmH7Y_zweXv-w"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/channel-33/id1058911614?mt=2"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://art19.com/shows/the-press-box"&gt;Art19&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/the-ringer/channel-33"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Channel33"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228878/the-jordan-doc-the-death-of-the-indie-bookstore-and-more"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21228878/the-jordan-doc-the-death-of-the-indie-bookstore-and-more</id>
    <author>
      <name>Bryan Curtis</name>
      <name>David Shoemaker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T09:06:48-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T09:06:48-04:00</updated>
    <title>Chris Paul Once Tattled on the Wolves for the Win </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nFKX4NBYsWYLXu04dTGnUVzpsTg=/240x0:1680x1080/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66677269/Site_Art___CP3.0.png" /&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Revisiting OKC’s incredible comeback in a December 2019 game against Minnesota&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="O9E64r"&gt;Chris Paul would do anything to win, even if it meant tattling on an opponent for checking into a game with his jersey untucked. Tyler Parker goes back to December 2019, when the Oklahoma City Thunder had an unbelievable comeback against the Minnesota Timberwolves thanks to Paul, Dennis Schröder, Steven Adams, and Jordan Bell’s untucked jersey. This is &lt;em&gt;The Ringer&lt;/em&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;NBA Defining Moments&lt;/em&gt; for the 2019-20 season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nr5f91"&gt;Check out the full &lt;em&gt;Defining Moments&lt;/em&gt; series here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/redirect?redir_token=kdlXPKuch0f2ADXZsL5LGDrU7px8MTU4NzQ3NDIxM0AxNTg3Mzg3ODEz&amp;amp;q=http%3A%2F%2Ftherin.gr%2F62IelmF&amp;amp;event=video_description&amp;amp;v=wtKcULjmI9w"&gt;http://therin.gr/62IelmF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/video/2020/4/20/21227805/chris-paul-once-tattled-on-the-wolves-for-the-win"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/video/2020/4/20/21227805/chris-paul-once-tattled-on-the-wolves-for-the-win</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tyler Parker</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T09:02:36-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T09:02:36-04:00</updated>
    <title>The ‘Final Fantasy VII Remake’ Exit Survey</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/a4yLRk10P1Ogr72SGvC88eNQjDQ=/67x0:1134x800/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66677259/FF7REmakeExitSurvey_SquareEnix_Ringer.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Square Enix/Ringer illustration&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The long-awaited release boldly reimagines a classic video game and adds a few unexpected twists&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SPmeHHjL18M3owxSCpIOb-dqaHU=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19912618/spoiler_warning_v2.2.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="DZ6hLF"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ten days ago, Square Enix released the long-anticipated &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/13/21218626/final-fantasy-vii-remake-cloud-strife"&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, an update of the classic 1997 video game, with spectacular graphics, real-time combat, voice acting, and some provocative revisions to the original plot. The remake covers just the opening act from the original game, exploring the capital city of Midgar—sequels are presumably coming in the next few years. For now, &lt;/em&gt;Ringer&lt;em&gt; staffers process what they’ve just played. Let’s mosey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="Fc892L"&gt;
&lt;p id="jLSWl4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your tweet-length review of &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="zMDWln"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/steveahlman"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Ahlman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An utterly beautiful, at times mind-blowing reimagination of a classic that has endured for over 20 years in the canon of great video games. To fans of the original, it’s a modern gaming dream realized with quite simply the best original score in video games. Bar none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="j3n5Cp"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/authors/chris-almeida"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Almeida&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: The planet is dying, but this game is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="x77aUe"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/authors/justin-charity"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justin Charity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Mature, sporty, and exotic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w8VuF2"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theringer.com/authors/rob-mahoney"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rob Mahoney&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; So good I have had to actively resist the urge to say it’s better than the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tp1VxZ"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; covers the first several hours of the original game and thus limits the player to exploring Midgar—a constraint that proved controversial during the game’s rollout. How do you feel about these limitations now that you’ve played the game?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tIcdh4"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; To make a game as epic and, quite frankly, as long as the original &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt; is a perfect idea in today’s era. &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; attempts to give the player an even more intimate look at Midgar, a beautiful city that is equal parts utopian and dystopian. It’s easy to imagine &lt;em&gt;Remake &lt;/em&gt;as a story with multiple parts. What I’m utterly baffled by is why this was not made crystal clear in &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;’s marketing rollout. Without the words “Part 1” on the side of that box, I don’t know how Square Enix thought people wouldn’t expect the entire &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt; story and experience. Nearly everyone I spoke to about this had no idea that it was not the full game. Bad call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="av6GIw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; Coming from the relatively sunny, blue, open-feeling world of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; felt a little claustrophobic. Walking through the city streets at night felt somewhat depressing. I’m aware that was supposed to be the vibe; being slowly killed by corporate overlords isn’t supposed to feel great. Still, I’m not spending a ton of time outside nowadays, so I like the simulated sun. I guess I can always just take a ride in &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R5fskcb__mU"&gt;Noctis’s Regalia&lt;/a&gt; to clear my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="T2qkCR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; I can’t believe there are so many players who sincerely wish&lt;em&gt; Remake&lt;/em&gt; was as overextended and thus underdeveloped and shallow as &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XV&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ckLAGP"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; Any concern I had that &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; might feel small or boxed in melted away when I saw the real Midgar for the first time. Flat, jumbled backgrounds have been rendered into scenes of unbelievable detail and sweeping beauty. Blowing out that portion of the story also grounds the game in human struggle and capitalist critique before things get all meteory. The only catch is the long wait for the next installment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O3pBth"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the biggest difference between the original game and the remake?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="u9Mkkz"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put: scale. Everything from the original game has been made larger, more beautiful, more grandiose, and more sweeping in &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;. Some might think of this as “filler”—padding out sections and characterization to fill out a near-30-hour story for just this first part alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pju93v"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; I was 3 when the original game came out and never owned the original PlayStation. My first exposure to the series was &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XII&lt;/em&gt;. This is a long way of saying that I never played the original—I just listened to the soundtrack. But this game certainly lived up to the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3COsHCsEf7I&amp;amp;t=0m53s"&gt;promises of its score&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8DfRh"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s the mechanical revisions, obviously: the real-time combat system, the dynamic camera, etc. There’s fewer characters, fewer summons, and fewer locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9Yphb6"&gt;But, to my mind, the characterizations are the biggest difference between the original game and &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;. There’s more work put into developing Barret, Tifa, and Aerith’s relationships with one another apart from their relationships with Cloud in &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MXr8op"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; The script. There’s a certain charm in &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;’s original, janky localization, but boy is it nice to have intelligible dialogue for a change. &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games will always be a certain kind of corny. Within that, there’s still room for actual humanity. Aerith has jokes now! Cloud isn’t just stoic, but socially inept! The development of the game’s writing, the caliber of the voice acting, and technological advancements that now allow for something as radical as a nose and mouth make all of the characters feel so much more complete. There’s some real subtlety to this game—something the series lost in its more recent installments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="x1qH7K"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"‘Final Fantasy VII Remake’ Earned Its Second Chance","url":"https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/13/21218626/final-fantasy-vii-remake-cloud-strife"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="V9k0e3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s talk about the voice acting in &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, which replaces the big blue text boxes in the original game. Does the voice acting serve the characters well?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AdP8EW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII &lt;/em&gt;fans know this isn’t the first time these characters have been given voiceovers. And I think the voice acting is pretty spectacular for both the characters and the ultimate translation of the Japanese source material. Even the small bits of dialogue from NPCs passing through the slums and city streets of Midgar give a truly lived feel to this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jx927g"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; I usually opt to play &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; games in Japanese with subtitles. I did that with &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;, too, and enjoyed it. I often find voiceovers clunky and awkward. I guess it was more or less reading text boxes over again, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Evzn54"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s one point when Aerith turns to Cloud, who’s pouting, as always, and says, “You mad?” It’s the little things said with such profound clarity about the core character dynamics that makes the voice acting great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-float-left"&gt;&lt;aside id="ExTC0X"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="newsletter" data-anthem-component-data='{"slug":"ringer_newsletter"}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yHrYaI"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; Absolutely. It likely helped in the writing, too; the original &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt; could never be fully voice acted because, to &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0466641/characters/nm0000148"&gt;borrow from Harrison Ford&lt;/a&gt;, you can type that shit, but you sure can’t say it. Making a real human person read the dialogue out loud polishes it, which allows the actors to bring it to life in a way that feels true to the tone of the story. This collection of actors nails it—the weirdness, the melodrama, the flirting, the whole thing. I even came around on John Eric Bentley’s performance as Barrett, which feels big and broad in part because it’s the act of a macho-posturing leader trying desperately to psych up himself and his team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WlLx50"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The remake lets the player shift their dominant perspective among four characters—Cloud, Barret, Tifa, and Aerith—in real-time combat. Who did you gravitate toward controlling in fights, and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Rl3dN0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; I think the battle system is truly inspired here. It strikes a great balance between the feel of real-time character action and the plodding nature of turn-based combat. I found myself switching back and forth between every single character as necessary. Is an enemy too far for Cloud’s immediate range? Switch to Barret and shoot it down. Need some healing or to inflict some status effects? Aerith has got you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="plO5BP"&gt;I absolutely loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lgDCJj"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; I tended to fight with Barret when given the option—I never became quite proficient enough at guarding and dodging to feel comfortable fighting on the inside. There was nothing that felt quite as satisfying as hitting a stunned enemy with a cross-slash, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qvqkZW"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; If you leave Tifa to the AI, then she’ll uppercut herself to death. If you control Tifa, then you can string her basic attacks and her special abilities into showstopping combinations. She’s a &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt; character in bullet time. So I tend to micromanage Tifa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7wfxJX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; All I want to do, even at this very moment, is pummel the shit out of monsters and robots with Tifa. They somehow gave a &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; game the pure satisfaction of a furious &lt;em&gt;Marvel vs. Capcom&lt;/em&gt;–style combo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFhtiW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; dedicates a lot more dramatic concern than the original game to the goofier Avalanche members, Jessie, Biggs, and Wedge. Did these characters grow on you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E6nPbK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; A fantastic call! I loved Biggs, Wedge, and Jessie in the original game and their characterization in &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; is pitch perfect and a brilliant counterpoint to Cloud’s cold attitude at the beginning of the game.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="N42k7f"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; I thought they were fun! Watching Jessie Thief-Lord her way into ecoterrorism was strangely compelling. Wedge provided necessary comic relief. It was nice to see them manage to get Cloud to soften up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TNMSaJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; Jessie grew on me. Biggs and Wedge didn’t. Ironically, Biggs and Wedge suffer Chewbacca Syndrome: &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; builds upon their characterization in the original game but plays too fast and loose with the tone, responsibilities, and stakes associated with them—especially in contrast with Jessie’s characterization—and so they’re neither sensible nor silly enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FH8sck"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; I wouldn’t say they grew on me so much as they existed for the first time. It had never really occurred to me that I should want to learn or care about the members of Avalanche. Their main purpose in the original game was as exposition-serving dialogue bots while you waited for the other party members to show up. &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; dispatches that idea from the jump by turning Jessie into a one-woman charm offensive, buying time for Biggs’s slow burn and … whatever it is that Wedge does. (Once more for the writers in the back: Eating is not a personality.) It’s a credit to the creators and performers involved that Jessie and Biggs, in particular, became the kinds of characters you’re glad to spend time with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IRE7q3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What, if anything, bugged you about the remake?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FZIHGc"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; At times, I felt like I was just walking down a hallway. It’s a beautiful hallway in the form of immaculately rendered set pieces with a soundtrack of rapturous music. But simply being ushered from one beautiful cutscene or fetch quest to the next between main story beats can be, at times, tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w5va3I"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; Sephiroth is way too sexy in &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt;. In fact, he’s way too charismatic in every project that has ever adapted him from the original game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jo9TZW"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;, Sephiroth is a deranged &lt;em&gt;Quillette&lt;/em&gt; reader who mutters nonsense about astronomy, archaeology, and genetics while vandalizing a local library in his unhinged passion for academic literature. He spends long stretches of the original game cradling a slimy, ancient corpse; he stinks, I presume. He’s only sexy in the sense that everyone imagines he’s sexy in the one, brief cutscene where he pouts while surrounded by flames in Nibelheim. Otherwise, Sephiroth seems messy, inarticulate, and repulsive in the extreme. It’s a great characterization! So I’ve always frowned upon the general tendency to reimagine Sephiroth as a winking boy band alumnus–turned-goth whose fanatical taunts may as well be pickup lines. &lt;em&gt;Hello, Cloud.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gTFi3r"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; I can’t say I enjoyed being assigned work by literal children. The early side quests in this game were the only thing that felt tedious—odd jobs that never amounted to much, in terms of characterization or reward. The magic of video games is that they make you happy to run errands. If that magic slips, you’re just a chump running around town looking for a lost cat, all in the hope that a little girl might get the word out that you’re a good mercenary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJ6bep"&gt;SPOILER ALERT: SERIOUSLY, DON’T CONTINUE READING IF YOU DON’T WANT TO LEARN ABOUT THE ENDGAME!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="usjyMM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you think about the, uh, choices that everyone (the characters, the game’s developers) made in the endgame?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pOygVv"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; I immediately want to say “stupid anime nonsense.” And that’s coming from a &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Hearts&lt;/em&gt; fan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PjR7xn"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally, Tetsuya Nomura tricked me into playing &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Hearts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1DlUrK"&gt;Seriously, I think the fateful timeline divergence from the original game was a strong call. The end of the highway really does mark the point where &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; might degrade from faithful reinvigoration into slavish retelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9x2f5l"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; What a thrill. Square Enix answered decades of fans’ pleading by remaking its most beloved game, and then immediately cracked it wide open to make something entirely new. It’s honestly a miracle that a game this big made with existing IP could be so self-aware. It’s the Greta Gerwig &lt;em&gt;Little Women&lt;/em&gt; of Final Fantasy games—as much about the story as it is the telling of that story. As we’re told throughout the game, &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; is all about reunion. Yet when long-time fans came back to the world of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;, they found that the invisible hand guiding the original game had been made visible, given a name, and turned into the final boss. Incredible. Now we just have to trust Tetsuya Nomura, the creative mind who took the &lt;em&gt;Kingdom Hearts&lt;/em&gt; series on a cosmic adventure up its own ass, to manage an open ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HvcH1c"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which should Square Enix prioritize for release: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Fantasy VII-2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; or &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Fantasy XVI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5xQX6e"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ahlman:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone following Square Enix’s track record during this current console generation knows it has had lackluster showings from both its licensed and in-house developed games for quite a while. &lt;em&gt;Remake&lt;/em&gt; was basically the ultimate lifeline for critical and commercial success. In case of emergency, remake &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt;. That being said, there is some true innovation when it comes to combat, storytelling, and—my god!—the music. Square Enix has brought a brilliant, albeit slightly flawed, epic back to life in this first part of the &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/em&gt; remake and it would be insane to not go full steam ahead with the second part for this next console generation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F0QePJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almeida:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;VII-2&lt;/em&gt;, no question. The game has sold phenomenally well over the last week and a half. Keep the momentum going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fritmH"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charity:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy VII-2&lt;/em&gt; could, essentially, be a sort of &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy XVI.&lt;/em&gt; It’s uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="c-end-para" id="v0RD36"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mahoney:&lt;/strong&gt; Considering that this was the first &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; single-player &lt;em&gt;Final Fantasy&lt;/em&gt; game in 17 years, let’s not overcomplicate this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nZTC5Z"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="on77jh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21227806/final-fantasy-vii-remake-exit-survey"/>
    <id>https://www.theringer.com/2020/4/20/21227806/final-fantasy-vii-remake-exit-survey</id>
    <author>
      <name>The Ringer Staff</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
