<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Vox -  All</title>
  <icon>https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52517/voxv.png</icon>
  <updated>2020-04-20T20:10:00-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T20:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T20:10:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Trump attacks a Republican governor for following his coronavirus testing advice</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="The White House Holds Daily Briefing On Coronavirus Pandemic" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/oS6DfaYTL4IC4HRZkLGPmYO6Yt0=/0x0:3263x2447/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66681295/1220011108.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Trump during the White House briefing on Monday. | Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Larry Hogan bought test kits from South Korea. Trump isn’t happy about it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="JsDk29"&gt;Gov. Larry Hogan (R-MD) followed President Donald Trump’s advice and took coronavirus testing into his own hands. Trump attacked him anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dmTfYB"&gt;Trump began Monday’s White House coronavirus briefing by criticizing Hogan — chair of the National Governors Association — for turning to foreign source to buy coronavirus tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yxFrQ2"&gt;“The governor of Maryland didn’t really understand,” Trump said, describing a call that Vice President Mike Pence had with governors earlier in the day to encourage them to do more to increase coronavirus testing on their own. “He didn’t really understand what was going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="2QCSbl"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"The governor of Maryland didn't really understand. He didn't really understand what was going on" -- Trump begins the April 20 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TrumpPressBriefing?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#TrumpPressBriefing&lt;/a&gt; by attacking Republican Gov. Larry Hogan of Maryland, who has been critical of the federal coronavirus response. &lt;a href="https://t.co/OTMwj6v5Sp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/OTMwj6v5Sp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Aaron Rupar (@atrupar) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atrupar/status/1252353071352475648?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="jL7Kjv"&gt;Trump was upset because Hogan and his wife — Yumi Hogan, a Korean immigrant — not only announced earlier Monday that they purchased 500,000 test kits from suppliers in South Korea, but also because Hogan indirectly criticized him &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/20/us/politics/larry-hogan-wife-yumi-korea-coronavirus-tests.html"&gt;during an interview with the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JIkywO"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;On Saturday, First Lady Yumi Hogan and I stood on the tarmac at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BWI_Airport?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BWI_Airport&lt;/a&gt; to welcome the first ever Korean Air passenger plane, carrying a very important payload of LabGun &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/COVID19?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#COVID19&lt;/a&gt; test kits which will give MD the capability of performing half a million coronavirus tests. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Elf0ADIRnJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Elf0ADIRnJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Governor Larry Hogan (@GovLarryHogan) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/GovLarryHogan/status/1252297144754716672?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="A17OAU"&gt;“The No. 1 problem facing us is lack of testing,” Hogan told the Times. “We can’t open up our states without ramping up testing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RsvyaA"&gt;“It should not have been this difficult,” he added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7LcSwf"&gt;CNN r&lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/04/20/politics/who-is-yumi-hogan/index.html"&gt;eported&lt;/a&gt; that Hogan’s wife, Yumi Hogan, “not only used her native language to help secure the tests but also helped negotiate the deal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9xTu4T"&gt;“The administration made it clear over and over again they want the states to take the lead, and we have to go out and do it ourselves, and that’s exactly what we did,” Hogan said during a news conference on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="w8IhYZ"&gt;Trump talks a big game about testing &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tHIXWr"&gt;Experts say &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/04/17/us/coronavirus-testing-states.html"&gt;the US needs to triple its testing capacity&lt;/a&gt; before it will be safe for businesses to reopen, but the number of tests completed daily has &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/17/21224872/coronavirus-testing-trump-reopen-economy"&gt;remained largely flat for the past month&lt;/a&gt;. Trump doesn’t seem to have an answer to this puzzle other than to turn the tables on governors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1oLczC"&gt;For instance, on Monday Trump trolled governors by flipping through a packet of papers that he said contained information about how they can better utilize lab capacity in their states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="Em0L6a"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Trump flips through a packet of paper that's meant to illustrate all the labs state governments could use to do more coronavirus testing (in other words it's a form of passing the buck) &lt;a href="https://t.co/brkRgvwqPa"&gt;pic.twitter.com/brkRgvwqPa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Aaron Rupar (@atrupar) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atrupar/status/1252357863437000704?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="hEVByx"&gt;But during an interview on CNN that coincided with the briefing, Hogan dismissed the value of the information Trump is sharing with governors, saying, “most of the governors already knew where the lab facilities were in their states.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GvTei0"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Maryland Gov. Larry Hogan:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Most of the governors already knew where the lab facilities were in their states. …most of the ones that they sent me in Maryland were all federal facilities…none of which were state-owned labs or facilities where we could actually do any testing." &lt;a href="https://t.co/UpO2IbeBDw"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UpO2IbeBDw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— JM Rieger (@RiegerReport) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RiegerReport/status/1252377508701298690?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="aFexmw"&gt;Trump, however, refuses to acknowledge there’s more he could do. Later during Monday’s briefing, the president suggested that governors like Hogan who have urged him to ramp up national testing efforts are part of a political conspiracy to bring him down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="P6XA84"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Trump suggests that demands for more testing, just like requests for ventilators, are part of a political conspiracy meant to take him down -- not necessary measures to respond to a virus that has killed more than 40,000 Americans &lt;a href="https://t.co/uFFBnqwgQP"&gt;pic.twitter.com/uFFBnqwgQP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Aaron Rupar (@atrupar) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atrupar/status/1252359716761550849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="2JR6Ka"&gt;Trump’s line in recent days has been to claim without evidence that other countries are reaching out to the US for help because testing here is going so great. Hogan’s announcement suggested that talk is a bunch of nonsense — and Trump wasn’t pleased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CsqUdt"&gt;At another point during Monday’s briefing, CNN’s Kaitlin Collins asked White House officials why Hogan would need to turn to South Korea for testing kits if it’s true, as Trump claims, that states already have enough testing capacity to begin the process of reopening business and schools. Nobody had a good answer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="z64iCC"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kaitlancollins?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@kaitlancollins&lt;/a&gt;: If we have enough tests now for everyone to go into phase one, why is the governor of Maryland having to get tests from South Korea? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;HHS OFFICIAL GIROIR: "I don't know what the governor of Maryland is doing in South Korea but there's excess capacity every day" &lt;a href="https://t.co/gnIWfewtTs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gnIWfewtTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Aaron Rupar (@atrupar) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atrupar/status/1252369240847339533?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="f24a99"&gt;Later, Trump returned to the podium and said that Hogan should’ve just called Mike Pence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nqrpbb"&gt;“The governor of Maryland could’ve called Mike Pence and saved a lot of money,” Trump said. “I think he needed to get a little knowledge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SaPY8w"&gt;But if it’s true that states have much more testing capacity than they’re currently utilizing, that hasn’t yet showed up in the daily testing numbers. And until it does, governors who don’t have connections in South Korea will likely find Trump’s bluster to be cold comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="EXmfaU"&gt;
&lt;p id="qdQVdY"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The news moves fast. To stay updated, follow &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atrupar"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aaron Rupar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; on Twitter, and read more of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vox’s policy and politics coverage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="phkvEu"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hnMHyn"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21228817/trump-larry-hogan-coronavirus-testing-kits"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21228817/trump-larry-hogan-coronavirus-testing-kits</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aaron Rupar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T17:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T17:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Facebook is taking down some, but not all, quarantine protest event pages</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="Protesters rally in downtown San Diego against California’s stay at home order to prevent the spread of the novel coronavirus, which causes COVID-19, on April 18, 2020. -" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/dCVI04WjKixgTsQSLdeeZ2mtb3g=/500x0:4500x3000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66680735/1210379392.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Facebook is taking down event pages for anti-stay-at-home rallies in some states. | Ariana Drehsler/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The company says it’s only taking down event pages in states where protests break social distancing rules. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="AfBfYC"&gt;Facebook is taking down some event pages promoting &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19/2020/4/19/21226922/coronavirus-stay-home-protests-texas-maryland-indiana-utah-new-hampshire"&gt;controversial anti-stay-at-home protests that are taking place across the US&lt;/a&gt; — but it’s only doing this in areas where the events violate local &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19"&gt;Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; social distancing rules. Facebook’s selective&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;response mirrors a larger fracture across the country as the Trump administration has &lt;a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/trump-tweets-to-liberate-michigan-minnesota-as-protesters-violate-orders-2020-4"&gt;given conflicting guidance&lt;/a&gt; about how and when restrictions should be lifted and has largely &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/03/why-theres-no-national-lockdown/609127/"&gt;left these decisions up to individual state politicians&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mv7ORX"&gt;The move comes after Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/19/pro-gun-activists-using-facebook-groups-push-anti-quarantine-protests/"&gt;faced criticism for allowing people to coordinate anti-quarantine protests&lt;/a&gt; on its platform. Public health officials, state officials, and health care workers say these protests are putting people’s lives at risk: By bringing people together in large crowds, they increase the chances of spreading the highly contagious disease. Others, including President Trump, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2020/04/20/coronavirus-latest-news/"&gt;have defended the protests&lt;/a&gt;, saying in a press conference on Monday that the protesters “love our country” and “want to get back to work.” Facebook’s decision to take down these posts comes at a time when the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2020/04/20/how-data-can-aid-fight-against-covid-19/"&gt;company is trying to step up as a leader in using big data&lt;/a&gt; to battle the virus’s spread while also &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/4/16/21223972/facebook-coronavirus-hoaxes-warning-misinformation-avaaz"&gt;battling efforts by some of its users to spread Covid-19 misinformation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xn3cTQ"&gt;Facebook confirmed to Recode that it will take down some posts organizing protests in areas &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/04/20/politics/facebook-covid-shutdown-protests/index.html"&gt;where the events go against local law&lt;/a&gt; — and for now, it’s only done so in&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;California, New Jersey, and Nebraska. In other states, such as Pennsylvania, users are continuing to promote anti-quarantine protests on Facebook, with as many as 60,000 members in one Pennsylvania group alone. In response to questions from Recode about why Facebook took down some posts but not others and concerns raised about them doing so, Facebook spokesperson Andy Stone sent the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rEk6ba"&gt;“Unless government prohibits the event during this time, we allow it to be organized on Facebook. For this same reason, events that defy government’s guidance on social distancing aren’t allowed on Facebook.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RxeLgn"&gt;The governors’ offices of New Jersey and Nebraska &lt;a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/technology/coronavirus-facebook-social-distancing-protests"&gt;told Fox News&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/04/20/politics/facebook-covid-shutdown-protests/index.html"&gt;and CNN&lt;/a&gt; that they had been in touch with Facebook about social distancing, but that they did not ask Facebook to take down the events. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yEUSp8"&gt;In recent weeks, a small number of people across the US have taken to the streets to protest Covid-19 shelter-in-place orders, arguing that people should be allowed to return to work and resume normal life, despite the risks to public health in doing so. Millions of Americans are facing economic hardships after an unprecedented shutdown of public life and nonessential businesses. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21225016/protests-stay-at-home-orders-trump-conservative-group-michigan"&gt;While polls show that&lt;/a&gt; a majority of Americans across party lines are afraid of prematurely ending social distancing, these protests are spreading across states. So far, anti-quarantine protesters number in the thousands, but they are a vocal minority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mRqcfW"&gt;These protests have been organized and gained publicity via Facebook’s events feature. While many of them appear to be organic posts started by concerned locals, reports &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/apr/18/coronavirus-americans-protest-stay-at-home"&gt;by the Guardian&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2020/04/19/pro-gun-activists-using-facebook-groups-push-anti-quarantine-protests/"&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; have revealed that many of them were actually started by established right-wing and pro-gun political groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gkhSez"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2020/apr/18/ohio-protest-repoen-viral-image-photojournalist-joshua-bickel"&gt;photographs&lt;/a&gt; and videos of these protests, many people are standing closer than 6 feet apart and without masks covering their faces, which poses a known public health risk to themselves and others. In one anti-lockdown protest in Colorado, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/health-care-workers-took-stand-against-protestors-opposing-coronavirus-lockdown-n1187711"&gt;local health care workers clashed with protesters,&lt;/a&gt; standing in front of them in their medical scrubs and protective gear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C6EWrr"&gt;Protest participants have argued they have a constitutional right to assemble. That’s one of the reasons why nonpartisan policy experts have raised concerns about precedents Facebook could set in shutting down efforts to organize these protests on its platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IZkyBy"&gt;Facebook has historically been a powerful platform for organizing protests in the US and elsewhere, from Black Lives Matter actions to the 2017 Charlottesville Unite the Right Rally — a violent white supremacist gathering that resulted in one murder and several injuries. (Facebook &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2017/8/14/16145086/facebook-twitter-charlottesville-terms-of-service-guidelines"&gt;eventually took down&lt;/a&gt; the main event page a day before the rally took place.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="a6gFHq"&gt;Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg has repeatedly defended the company’s role in &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/10/17/20919505/mark-zuckerberg-georgetown-free-speech-facebook"&gt;protecting free speech on its platform&lt;/a&gt;, particularly around politics. Many are arguing that the anti-quarantine protests should fall under that protection and that people’s civil liberties are at risk if Facebook shuts down such events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h975AC"&gt;But others say that while individual rights to protest are at stake, so is the health of the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iJOYn9"&gt;“The problem isn’t civil liberties because these groups can build their own webpages and carry out conversation there,” Joan Donovan, the director of Harvard University’s Technology and Social Change Research Project, told Recode. “The overarching question is, ‘does Facebook have a responsibility to protect their users from health misinformation?’ If you think they should, then these actions are the correct course of action.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="aWT7Xw"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TOlabf"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/4/20/21228224/facebook-coronavirus-covid-19-protests-taking-down-content-moderation-freedom-speech-debate"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/4/20/21228224/facebook-coronavirus-covid-19-protests-taking-down-content-moderation-freedom-speech-debate</id>
    <author>
      <name>Shirin Ghaffary</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T17:15:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T17:15:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>America’s Coffee Shops Just Might Survive This Moment </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BZPl2uaUJrtLwvb7CdfhMTN2zDc=/197x0:1374x883/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66680644/shutterstock_1705982779.0.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://www.shutterstock.com/g/phototimedp" target="_blank"&gt;phototimedp&lt;/a&gt;/Shutterstock&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you compare the situation to the ongoing restaurant apocalypse, there’s some hopeful news coming out of the coffee landscape&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.eater.com/2020/4/20/21227910/coffee-shops-affected-by-coronavirus-pandemic-pivots"&gt;https://www.eater.com/2020/4/20/21227910/coffee-shops-affected-by-coronavirus-pandemic-pivots&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.eater.com/2020/4/20/21227910/coffee-shops-affected-by-coronavirus-pandemic-pivots"/>
    <id>https://www.eater.com/2020/4/20/21227910/coffee-shops-affected-by-coronavirus-pandemic-pivots</id>
    <author>
      <name>Eater</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T17:00:53-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T17:00:53-04:00</updated>
    <title>Coronavirus stimulus money will be wasted on fossil fuels</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/4k7476kWUFkOZxwtt13FWjU0iFo=/137x0:2804x2000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66677735/GettyImages_1209295645.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Low gas prices in Old Orchard Beach, Maine, on March 30. | Derek Davis/Portland Press Herald via Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;Oil and gas companies were already facing structural problems before Covid-19 and are in long-term decline.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="pydcqP"&gt;As countries across the world go into lockdown in response to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19"&gt;Covid-19&lt;/a&gt;, economies are in free fall. Almost every sector is taking a hit, hemorrhaging jobs and value. And almost every sector will be shaped, for years to come, by the speed, amount, and nature of public assistance it receives. There is a finite amount of time, resources, and political will available to get economies going again; not every sector will get what it wants or needs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4HKHOw"&gt;In short, the decisions legislators make in response to the coronavirus crisis will have an enormous influence on what kind of economies emerge on the other side. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="I301Hj"&gt;A few weeks ago, I wrote about &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/3/25/21180248/just-sustainable-economic-response-coronavirus-explained"&gt;what an ideal recovery and stimulus package would look like&lt;/a&gt;. And last week I wrote about how shortsighted it is for Republicans (enabled by learned Democratic passivity) to &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/4/16/21220312/coronavirus-stimulus-renewable-energy-democrats"&gt;reject aid for the struggling clean energy industry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JjtNS9"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;BREAKING: WTI crude oil futures trade at negative price for first time &lt;a href="https://t.co/pOSyH6AVtP"&gt;https://t.co/pOSyH6AVtP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/XsoH1jG8WH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XsoH1jG8WH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Bloomberg (@business) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/business/status/1252298699792883713?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="JpsEUz"&gt;In this post, I want to take a look at why it is equally shortsighted for President Trump and congressional Republicans to remain so devoted to the fossil fuel industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4DLKV"&gt;The dominant narrative is still that fossil fuels are a pillar of the US economy, with giant companies like Exxon Mobil&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;producing revenue and jobs that the US can’t afford to do without. Even among those eager to address climate change by moving&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;past fossil fuels to clean energy&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;— a class that includes &lt;a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/248006/americans-support-reducing-fossil-fuel.aspx"&gt;a majority of Americans&lt;/a&gt; — there is a lingering mythology that US fossil fuels are, to use the familiar phrase, too big to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/OeQHCVujN5qMDq4xVR1Tu44OUOQ=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19911114/1209081392.jpg.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Jim Watson/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;President Trump, flanked by House Minority Leader Kevin McCarthy, left, and Chevron CEO Mike Wirth, meets with energy sector CEOs at the White House on April 3.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="2DxtVZ"&gt;But the position of fossil fuels in the US economy is less secure than it might appear. In fact, the fossil fuel industry is facing substantial structural challenges that will be exacerbated by, but will not end with, the Covid-19 crisis. For years, the industry has been shedding value, taking on debt, losing favor among financial institutions and &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/10/opinion/sunday/coronavirus-texas-fracking-layoffs.html"&gt;investors&lt;/a&gt;, and turning more and more to lobbying governments to survive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UjbLxa"&gt;It is, in short, a turkey. CNBC financial analyst &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/business-and-finance/2020/4/6/21206029/jim-cramer-interview-cnbc-stock-market-coronavirus"&gt;Jim Cramer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://oilprice.com/Energy/Energy-General/Jim-Cramer-Fossil-Fuels-Are-Done.html"&gt;put it best&lt;/a&gt;, back in late January, before Covid-19 had even become a crisis in the US: “I’m done with fossil fuels. They’re done. They’re just done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6zQ9bq"&gt;“We’re in the death knell phase,” he said “The world has turned on [fossil fuels].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y5cUh9"&gt;Cramer’s take is not yet conventional wisdom, but he’s right. Evidence in support appears in a new report from the Center for International Environmental Law (CIEL) called “&lt;a href="https://www.ciel.org/reports/pandemic-crisis-systemic-decline/"&gt;Pandemic Crisis, Systemic Decline&lt;/a&gt;.” Let’s walk through it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="C22yJu"&gt;Fossil fuels are furiously lobbying for, and receiving, largesse from the US government&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tmUbkB"&gt;The UK-based think tank InfluenceMap recently did an &lt;a href="https://influencemap.org/report/The-Coronavirus-Crisis-and-Climate-Lobbying-23249d39450ff19b441090a6a50174eb"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; that tracks corporate lobbying in the face of the Covid-19 crisis. It found that, across the globe, the oil and gas sector has been the most active in lobbying for interventions, seeking, as CIEL summarizes, “direct and indirect support, including bailouts, buyouts, regulatory rollbacks, exemption from measures designed to protect the health of workers and the public, non-enforcement of environmental laws, and criminalization of protest, among others.” In Canada, Australia, and the UK, the industry is arguing that it must be subsidized and deregulated in order to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cJobgp"&gt;In the US alone, the industry is seeking access to a range of stimulus funds, relief from a variety of pollution regulations, and use of the strategic petroleum reserve to bolster prices. Journalist Amy Westervelt is tracking &lt;a href="https://www.drillednews.com/post/will-pandemic-relief-become-a-petroleum-industry-slush-fund"&gt;at least a dozen other lobbying efforts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1H6drI"&gt;The petrochemical and plastics industry, which is in large part an extension of the oil and gas industry, is exploiting the crisis as well. It has &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/states/f/?id=00000171-0d87-d270-a773-6fdfcc4d0000"&gt;lobbied&lt;/a&gt; the federal government to declare an official preference for single-use plastic bags and &lt;a href="https://www.edie.net/library/Coronavirus-and-plastics--Are-we-distancing-our-way-back-towards-single-use-/6970"&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; that more fresh produce should be wrapped in plastic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hMPcKd"&gt;The virus has not slowed down the Trump administration’s attempts to assist the industry. It is &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/4/2/21202509/trump-climate-change-fuel-economy-standards-coronavirus-pandemic-peak"&gt;gutting fuel economy standards&lt;/a&gt;, which, by its own estimation, will increase pollution and &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/science/archive/2020/04/trumps-auto-rollback-will-eliminate-13500-jobs-cafe/609748/"&gt;eliminate 13,500 jobs a year&lt;/a&gt;. The EPA has &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/26/climate/epa-coronavirus-pollution-rules.html"&gt;dramatically eased the enforcement of pollution regulations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://news.bloombergenvironment.com/environment-and-energy/secret-science-rule-could-limit-epa-virus-efforts-carper-says"&gt;moved forward with its “secret science” rule&lt;/a&gt;, which will make it more difficult to understand and address the health impacts of air pollution — and more difficult to study the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;&lt;div class="c-image-grid"&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NI3PV5UkJL9F6ZNGDZt7Lixmnfc=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19912702/GettyImages_1204027600.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The petrochemical industry has lobbied the federal government to declare an official preference for single-use plastic bags.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="c-image-grid__item"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cqUYAeeULkKEm658BF_YDB1TKXc=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19912682/GettyImages_1161487992.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Jeff Swensen/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;President Trump delivers a speech on energy sector jobs at the Shell Chemicals Petrochemical Complex in Monaca, Pennsylvania, on August 13, 2019.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="W0eLSu"&gt;During a supply glut driven by historically low prices, the Interior Department is rushing to lease federal land for oil and gas development, despite an &lt;a href="https://business.financialpost.com/pmn/business-pmn/u-s-gulf-oil-lease-sale-is-weakest-since-2016"&gt;anemic response&lt;/a&gt;, rock-bottom prices, and &lt;a href="http://www.conservativestewards.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/CRS-TCS-Lease-Suspension-PR_03_19-_20.pdf"&gt;calls from conservative and taxpayer groups&lt;/a&gt; to suspend leasing in the face of the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UarWYw"&gt;The administration seems &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/03/10/trump-oil-bailout/"&gt;determined to bail out struggling shale gas companies&lt;/a&gt;, despite that overleveraged, debt-ridden sector being &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2020-03-12/shale-frackers-need-consolidation-not-a-trump-bailout?sref=Zd9D2evu"&gt;long overdue for a shakeout&lt;/a&gt;. (For more on that, check out &lt;a href="https://www.drillednews.com/post/will-pandemic-relief-become-a-petroleum-industry-slush-fund"&gt;Amy Westervelt’s reporting at Drilled&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yhd9QX"&gt;Trump is &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/12/business/energy-environment/opec-russia-saudi-arabia-oil-coronavirus.html"&gt;negotiating with Saudi Arabia and Russia&lt;/a&gt; on oil supply cuts, and has the Department of Energy &lt;a href="https://www.worldoil.com/news/2020/4/14/doe-working-to-lease-out-23-mmbbl-of-strategic-petroleum-reserve-capacity"&gt;buying up billions of tons of oil&lt;/a&gt; for the strategic petroleum reserve, all to try to boost the price of oil to help &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/policy/energy-environment/491111-oil-giants-meet-at-white-house-amid-talk-of-buying-strategic"&gt;struggling oil majors&lt;/a&gt;. A group of GOP senators is &lt;a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/business/energy/article/Republican-Senators-Want-to-Help-Coal-Get-U-S-15189180.php"&gt;lobbying for fossil fuel companies&lt;/a&gt;, including coal companies, to be eligible for the small-business recovery fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xAnkEQ"&gt;Last week, EPA Administrator Andrew Wheeler announced that the administration, in defiance of an enormous body of evidence and &lt;a href="https://www.eenews.net/stories/1062872411"&gt;recommendations from EPA scientists and staff&lt;/a&gt;, will &lt;a href="https://www.union-bulletin.com/news/national/epa-won-t-tighten-rule-for-emissions-tied-to-respiratory-illness/article_85f42c51-8247-50b5-87a7-7f0bcbec569e.html"&gt;not tighten restrictions on soot pollution&lt;/a&gt;. And on Friday, Wheeler announced that the EPA will &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/16/climate/epa-mercury-coal.html"&gt;weaken standards on mercury and other toxic metals&lt;/a&gt; from fossil-fueled power plants, again in opposition to the scientific consensus, based on rigged cost-benefit analysis that &lt;a href="https://www.rff.org/publications/journal-articles/deep-flaws-mercury-regulatory-analysis/"&gt;deliberately excluded most benefits&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BkZkfU"&gt;Across the board, the administration is doing everything it can to help fossil fuels. But it’s a mug’s game. The industry is faltering for reasons that well predate Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7Z7bFf"&gt;Fossil fuels were already facing structural problems before the coronavirus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="lOkd5Q"&gt;US coal is in terminal decline, for reasons I’ve written about &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/3/14/21177941/climate-change-coal-renewable-energy"&gt;many times before&lt;/a&gt;. No amount of stimulus money or weaker pollution regulations can save it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LYqZ1Y"&gt;But on the surface, things look different for oil and gas. &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/a-decade-in-which-fracking-rocked-the-oil-world-11576630807"&gt;Thanks to fracking&lt;/a&gt;, production has been booming for the past decade, vaulting the US ahead of Saudi Arabia and Russia to become the the world’s leading oil and gas producer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="8n6R1H"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Coal left Appalachia devastated. Now it’s doing the same to Wyoming.","url":"https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/7/9/20684815/coal-wyoming-bankruptcy-blackjewel-appalachia"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="JARmgf"&gt;And the same goes for petrochemicals and especially plastics, which have been &lt;a href="http://www3.weforum.org/docs/WEF_The_New_Plastics_Economy.pdf"&gt;forecast&lt;/a&gt; to be the main drivers of rising petroleum demand in coming years. The industry has issued rosy projections of plastics’ growth and invested $200 billion in new petrochemical and plastics infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KELU42"&gt;But dig below the surface and things don’t look so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5SLEi2"&gt;First, fracking was a &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@foe_us/no-bailout-for-fracking-2cfa50b36f2b"&gt;financial wreck&lt;/a&gt; long before Covid-19 hit. US fracking operations have been losing money for a decade, to the tune of around $280 billion. Overproduction has produced a supply glut, low prices, and an accumulating surplus in storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jTubw3"&gt;CIEL reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="lv3je3"&gt;Since 2015, over 200 drillers have gone bankrupt, with 32 declaring bankruptcy in 2019. At the beginning of 2020, the industry continued to struggle as natural gas prices remained low due to sluggish demand growth. By the end of the first quarter, another seven drillers had declared bankruptcy, six additional drillers had their credit outlook downgraded, and several major banks had written down the expected value of many drillers’ reserves. A recent analysis from Rystad Energy indicated that, at prevailing oil and gas prices, almost all new fracking wells drilled would lose money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="dmagxs"&gt;Even as its prospects grow dimmer, the enormous debt the industry has taken on over the years is coming back to bite it. Some $40 billion will come due this year alone, and around $200 billion in the next four years. In the hours after this article was first published on April 20, oil futures for May fell to &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-04-19/oil-drops-to-18-year-low-on-global-demand-crunch-storage-woes?utm_content=business&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;cmpid=socialflow-twitter-business&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=socialflow-organic&amp;amp;__twitter_impression=true"&gt;negative prices&lt;/a&gt;. Mind-boggling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fbWpWf"&gt;Second, both oil and gas prices were persistently low leading into 2019. Due to oversupply and mild winters in the US and Europe, there is a glut of both natural gas and oil, such that the entire world’s spare oil storage is in danger of being filled. Many big oil deals in “frontier countries” with as-yet-unexploited reserves, like Guyana, Argentina, and Mozambique, are falling through as low prices drag on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="E5VCl2"&gt;Third, renewable energy and electric vehicles are threatening oil and gas’s dominance in both transportation, which represents 70 percent of global demand, and electricity. Natural gas’s status as a “bridge fuel” in the power sector is in &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/7/13/17551878/natural-gas-markets-renewable-energy"&gt;increasing doubt&lt;/a&gt;; since 2014, orders for new gas turbines (to generate power) have &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-ge-pow-erplants/ge-books-more-power-plant-orders-beats-mitsubishi-siemens-sources-idUSKCN1SK26T"&gt;fallen by half&lt;/a&gt;. As for transportation, a &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mikescott/2019/09/02/economics-of-electric-vehicles-mean-oils-days-as-a-transport-fuel-are-numbered/#50e68d3c5102"&gt;recent report&lt;/a&gt; from the international banking group BNP Paribas concluded that “the economics of oil for gasoline and diesel vehicles versus wind- and solar-powered EVs are now in relentless and irreversible decline.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cTkciZK4vaw29sWGqqWsOR6Tyd8=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19912715/GettyImages_1208282996.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Sven Hoppe/picture alliance via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;An electric car at a charging station in Bavaria, Germany, on March 26, 2020.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="OQqtSA"&gt;Fourth, oil and gas majors are revealing their own weakness by writing down assets — effectively conceding that certain reserves cannot be profitably exploited. In 2019, Chevron wrote down $11 billion worth; Spanish oil company Repsol recently wrote down $5 billion worth. Exxon Mobil, after adding Canadian tar sands assets to its books in 2017, reversed course and wrote down 3.2 billion barrels last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g4Bktc"&gt;Fifth, financial institutions — “institutional and retail investors, banks, insurers, and credit rating agencies” — are catching wind of fossil fuels’ weakness and beginning to back away. Many, like Wells Fargo, BlackRock, the European Investment Bank, and the World Bank Group, are restricting investments in carbon-intensive projects. As of March 2020, asset investors worth $12 trillion had &lt;a href="https://www.divestinvest.org/"&gt;declared that they would divest from fossil fuels&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mhO2cU"&gt;As financial institutions divest, the ones still invested in carbon-intensive projects face increasing vulnerability to lawsuits charging them with ignoring material risks. “As the risks of investing in the oil and gas sector become ever more apparent,” CIEL writes, “more and more investors subject to fiduciary duties will likely choose to steer clear of these companies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="w98Tb7"&gt;Like these other dismal trends, the financial turn from fossil fuels was underway well before Covid-19. Over the past decade, companies in the sector have spent more on stock buybacks and dividends than they have brought in through revenue, leading to a greater and greater debt burden. Declining confidence in the sector has made it the worst-performing sector on the S&amp;amp;P Index. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/6y4pE2Tqh_iTAee7VW1VzMGGhng=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19910167/Screen_Shot_2020_04_17_at_11.48.18_PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a class="ql-link" href="https://us.spindices.com/indices/equity/dow-jones-us-oil-gas-index" target="_blank"&gt;S&amp;amp;P Dow Jones Indices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The Dow Jones Index (black line) vs. the Dow Jones Oil &amp;amp; Gas Index (blue line), as of April 17, 2020.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="PeMK7n"&gt;Finally, plastics, the great hope of the oil and gas sector, do not appear to be growing fast enough to justify the industry’s optimistic projections. Much of the US plastics industry is geared for export, but countries across the world (127 and counting) are adopting restrictions on single-use plastics. The most recent such restrictions were &lt;a href="https://www.icis.com/explore/resources/news/2020/01/24/10461510/insight-china-ban-on-single-use-plastics-threatens-4m-tonnes-year-of-polymer-demand"&gt;adopted by China&lt;/a&gt;, the world’s largest plastic producer and consumer. Plastics, like oil and gas, are suffering from the dual malady of overexpansion and underconsumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KTB9v7"&gt;As an example that encompasses all these structural problems, CIEL cites Exxon Mobil. The company’s plan for growth involves growth in its petrochemical operations, which is now in doubt; fracking in the Permian Basin, which is now in doubt; and expanding oil production in Guyana, which is now (owing to political instability) in doubt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4owKaU"&gt;All these doubts are converging as Moody’s recently revised the company’s outlook to negative. It fell out of the S&amp;amp;P’s top 10 for the first time, its stock hit its lowest price in a decade, the rapid rise of renewables and electric vehicles rendered billions (and perhaps soon trillions) of dollars of its assets worthless, and it is keeping shareholders happy with debt-financed dividends. The Institute for Energy Economics and Financial Analysis found that over the past decade, Exxon Mobil has &lt;a href="https://ieefa.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/Living-Beyond-Their-Means-Five-Oil-Majors-Cannot-Cover-Dividends_January-2020.pdf"&gt;spent $64.5 billion more on payouts to stockholders than it earned in free cash flow&lt;/a&gt;. That can’t go on much longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Y0QT2j"&gt;Again: All of these structural trends predate Covid-19. But the global lockdown in response to the virus has accelerated all of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="jl6dQt"&gt;Oil and gas are caught in a historic downturn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="A5HhGo"&gt;Into this already dismal situation for fossil fuels came the virus and the subsequent lockdown. The vertiginous plunge in consumer demand has hit every sector of the economy, but oil and gas, already facing oversupply and persistent low prices, were particularly vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="teKmAe"&gt;“Oil, gas, and petrochemical stocks have been affected more rapidly and much more deeply than almost any other sector,” CIEL writes. “The oil and gas sector lost more than 45% of its total value from the beginning of January to early April 2020.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J6rQiv"&gt;The already declining stocks of Exxon Mobil, Royal Dutch Shell, and Occidental Petroleum were sent tumbling even faster. In July 2014, Exxon stock hit a high of $107; as of early April 2020, it was at $42, its lowest level in decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0bQd7B"&gt;Transportation represents 70 percent of petroleum consumption, but no one is moving. Rystad Energy &lt;a href="https://www.rystadenergy.com/globalassets/pdfs/rystad-energy_covid-19-report_1-april-2020_public-access.pdf"&gt;estimates&lt;/a&gt; that as of March 2020, global traffic is down 40 percent. As lockdowns remain, that number will likely drop further.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Hfboh2"&gt;Air travel has been the fastest-growing source of demand for transport fuels, but &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/4/20/21224080/coronavirus-air-travel-decline-charts"&gt;no one is flying&lt;/a&gt;. “In the final week of March 2020,” CIEL writes, “commercial air traffic was almost 63% lower than in 2019.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/1hlSoGRJgRwnxt-bMzTlYyCYrjk=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19913417/covid_airline_chart.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Christina Animashaun/Vox&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="AQ3MZt"&gt;Public health officials warn that there could be periodic outbreaks for months or even years. Meanwhile, there are rapid advances being made everywhere in the infrastructure, technology, and practices of working remotely, from home. It’s entirely possible that auto and air travel won’t reach their pre-virus levels in the US for years, if ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RY8e05"&gt;Travel by ship is also taking a hit. Cruise ships, beset by a series of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/2/25/21152903/coronavirus-cruise-ship-outbreak-cruises-sexual-assault-environment"&gt;viral horror stories&lt;/a&gt;, have suspended operations and many analysts doubt they will ever fully recover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V4AokV"&gt;Meanwhile, oversupply, exacerbated by the drop in demand, is taxing the nation’s storage capacity — the International Energy Agency says global capacity is about &lt;a href="https://www.chron.com/business/energy/article/Crude-oil-storage-tanks-filling-up-as-gasoline-15202290.php?mkt_tok=eyJpIjoiWWprNFlXUTNNREppWlRrNSIsInQiOiIwTE5ZeGIxMDVvaWxmbmxDZHFtTHVXR2lHQlZNa1NONlA1VyszKzhjZDJxcDZJZ2hhc2RYMVprY0lLekx0b0dQWk9OdkZ5Mjl5Uk41ZTBVdEk4UGNDNU9BQ0JzZ3NBMFFxR3ZRcDc3blF2OVNESnNoMk9RdDZPckZZMEpZdU1wZSJ9"&gt;85 percent full&lt;/a&gt;. “Nearly all observers have concluded that at projected levels of demand destruction,” CIEL writes, “the total global capacity for storing unneeded oil and gas will soon be exceeded.” At that point, many producers will be forced to simply &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-global-oil-shale-bust-insight/oil-in-the-age-of-coronavirus-a-u-s-shale-bust-like-no-other-idUSKCN21X0HC"&gt;shut down operations&lt;/a&gt; and write-downs will accelerate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uOv5HD"&gt;On top of all this has come a price war between Saudi Arabia and Russia, competing for the shrinking supply left over by the US supply glut. Global oil prices were at $69 per barrel in January 2020. The price of a barrel of Canadian tar sands oil appears &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/bitumen-wcs-wti-oil-1.5511386"&gt;headed into negative prices&lt;/a&gt;, as are &lt;a href="https://business.financialpost.com/pmn/business-pmn/texas-oil-at-2-a-barrel-raises-specter-of-negative-prices"&gt;Texas oil&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://pgjonline.com/news/2020/03-march/us-gas-prices-turn-negative-at-texas-waha-hub"&gt;natural gas&lt;/a&gt; in some parts of the US, for May futures (&lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/oil-price-monday-1.5538048"&gt;June prices are higher&lt;/a&gt;). The so-called OPEC+ group of oil-producing nations (OPEC + Russia) recently agreed to a 10 million barrel a day cut in production, but &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/13/business/economy/coronavirus-oil-opec-trump.html"&gt;analysts agree&lt;/a&gt; that it is &lt;a href="https://oilprice.com/Energy/Crude-Oil/The-Sad-Truth-About-The-OPEC-Production-Cut.html"&gt;unlikely to be sufficient to stabilize prices&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="c-wide-block"&gt;  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/2XQxGKjiEdd3h8STmRPwvt1Ul2U=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19912733/GettyImages_1209826766.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Igor Onuchin/TASS via Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Freight trains filled with oil in Krasnodar, Russia, on April 14. As supply exceeds demand and oil prices fall, oil producers find themselves confronted with storage challenges.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="uTRSeC"&gt;When storage capacity runs out, producers are forced to pay people to take oil off their hands. (Raise your hand if you had “&lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/01/coronavirus-oil-prices-could-turn-negative-as-storage-nears-capacity.html"&gt;negative oil prices&lt;/a&gt;” on your 21st-century bingo card.) Even if storage doesn’t completely run out, it will be close to full, serving to suppress prices, for years. Petrochemicals and plastics don’t have it much better, with major investors delaying or dropping out of projects left and right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0sg6fn"&gt;“In the medium term,” CIEL writes, “the prospect of a full recovery for many of these revenue streams is, at best, uncertain, and, in many cases, unlikely.” Fossil fuels and petrochemicals could struggle for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RTgtmh"&gt;And even if they eventually manage to achieve something like their pre-virus trajectory, that trajectory was sloping downward. As CIEL summarizes: “the pandemic exposes and exacerbates fundamental weaknesses throughout the sector that both predate the current crisis and will outlast it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7ehUD0"&gt;Wasting stimulus money on fossil fuels makes no sense, so Trump will probably do it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vKuW9l"&gt;Slowly but surely, the world is beginning to take global warming seriously, shifting attention and investment to materials and sources of energy that do not produce greenhouse gas emissions. As more and more jurisdictions, institutions, and investors turn away from fossil fuels, explicitly citing climate change, those left holding carbon-intensive assets will become targets of increasingly intense legal and civic activism holding them responsible for the damages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJJ2oB"&gt;CIEL concludes with recommendations to investors, frontier countries, and local communities: Take heed of fossil fuels’ long-term weakness when making decisions about the future. CIEL also argues that public officials “should not waste limited response and recovery resources on bailouts, debt relief, or similar supports for oil, gas, and petrochemical companies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5Q6uyX"&gt;Given the well-established inclinations of Trump and congressional Republicans, that recommendation is likely to fall on deaf ears, at least in the US. If Democrats do not muster the courage to stop them — and it &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2020/4/16/21220312/coronavirus-stimulus-renewable-energy-democrats"&gt;does not seem they will&lt;/a&gt; — the GOP is likely to continue showering the fossil fuel industry with favors while dismissing aid to the clean energy industry as frivolous. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="President Trump Signs Coronavirus Stimulus Bill In The Oval Office" data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-1da44G9Il2Ky86W9xVkPfbd66M=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19911152/1208433576.jpg.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Erin Schaff-Pool/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;President Trump signs the $2 trillion stimulus bill on March 27, 2020. Not a crew likely to turn their backs on fossil fuels.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="GTUZPE"&gt;At best, they can slow down the transition to clean energy a bit. They cannot stop it. Adding stimulus money to fossil fuels’ already &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2017/10/6/16428458/us-energy-coal-oil-subsidies"&gt;subsidy-rich diet&lt;/a&gt; will allow a little more pollution and a little more damage to public health for a little longer, but it’s only a delay. Meanwhile, other countries will be establishing a commanding position in some of the biggest growth industries of the 21st century. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mKYNT8"&gt;It would be a shame to emerge from this crisis still clinging to the past rather than facing, and preparing for, the future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y99ZHs"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, April 20, 4 pm ET&lt;/strong&gt;: After this article was first published, oil futures fell to negative prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="iJOYn9"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vOuWms"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21224659/coronavirus-stimulus-money-oil-prices-fossil-fuels-bailout"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21224659/coronavirus-stimulus-money-oil-prices-fossil-fuels-bailout</id>
    <author>
      <name>David Roberts</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T15:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T15:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>What 2 new studies teach us about our socially distant future</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="People in a socially distanced line stand outside a pharmacy." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/SCG0K4GKT3IxY8Cuq5GPotBax5c=/497x0:5830x4000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66680129/GettyImages_1210412986.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;The end of social distancing and lockdowns should happen gradually, because we know they are working to contain the Covid-19 coronavirus. | Ron Adar/Echoes Wire/Barcroft Media via Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;New research shows social distancing works —&amp;nbsp;and why we must relax it gradually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="cpswiR"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jPdkK3"&gt;There is something challenging to communicate in &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19"&gt;coronavirus&lt;/a&gt; reporting: Nearly 41,000 people &lt;a href="https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/map.html"&gt;have died from Covid-19&lt;/a&gt; in the United States (and many more will die), and those deaths have come despite the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/science-and-health/2020/3/26/21192211/coronavirus-covid-19-social-distancing-end"&gt;unprecedented social distancing measures&lt;/a&gt; being taken across the country. Without them, the loss of life would surely be higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vqjoyU"&gt;Unless or until scientists have data to back it up, though, the impact of social distancing is as much hypothesis and intuition as scientific fact. Luckily, a new study out of Hong Kong indicates that the precautious taken there — similar to those taken in the US, like closed schools, travel restrictions, mask-wearing, and general distancing — have had a measurable effect on the spread of Covid-19 and the flu. That should give people confidence that social distancing is working, even with its painful economic toll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aDhTWJ"&gt;But as Americans consider when and how to begin relaxing those measures, they will have to balance health concerns with economic ones. That’s where another new study, this one from economists at the University of Chicago and Penn State, comes in handy. It reaches a useful conclusion: The best way to ease these lockdowns and alleviate the economic losses without inviting an untenable spike in cases and fatalities is to do it gradually — over a matter of months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V64ady"&gt;Taken together, these new studies offer a picture of America’s socially distant future: Even as people try to resume something resembling normal life, it will take time — and precautionary measures will have to be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="TczBnG"&gt;Social distancing has demonstrably impeded Covid-19’s spread in Hong Kong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4lyipG"&gt;Hong Kong has taken many of the same steps the United States has to stave off the Covid-19 threat. It started closing schools and restricting travel from the Chinese hot spots in January. It has added new migration rules as well as mandatory quarantines for overseas travelers in the last few months and set up protocols for civil servants to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6dKnpV"&gt;In addition, the public has responded by changing their behavior. According to &lt;a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanpub/article/PIIS2468-2667(20)30090-6/fulltext?utm_campaign=tlcoronavirus20&amp;amp;utm_content=126713203&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;hss_channel=tw-758678085176795136#%20"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this new study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, led by researchers from the WHO Collaborating Centre for Infectious Disease Epidemiology and Control in Hong Kong, most people say they are avoiding crowded places (85 percent in March) and staying home as much as possible (75 percent). People are practicing better hygiene, too: The percentage who said they wear masks jumped from 75 percent in January to 99 percent in March, and the percentage who say they wash their hands more than usual leaped from 71 percent to 95 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XPQAEB"&gt;And as a result, local transmission in Hong Kong appears to be quite low. The metric used to measure transmission — which estimates how many people someone carrying the virus will infect — has hovered around 1. The goal is to push the threshold below 1, which if sustained will lead to the outbreak being contained. But even holding at around 1 is a success, compared to what we’d expect in nature (the virus has an estimated R0 of 2 to 2.25, though it’s still not clear exactly how contagious it is.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n7qCKH"&gt;The main reason Hong Kong saw a spike in Covid-19 cases in mid-March was because there was a sudden surge in cases imported from other countries (and Hong Kong started testing asymptomatic inbound travelers and requiring quarantines in response). This chart shows that locally sourced cases remain quite low and steady, allowing for the increase you would expect after people brought the virus onto the island from elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NxABs04xVSFUoOBAMPj_4J_5-7s=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19913589/gr2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;The Lancet&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="ugKuuY"&gt;But what’s great about this study is the authors don’t just rely on Covid-19 cases. They also tracked influenza infections over the same period and they found a notable downturn compared to prior years when schools were closed but no other social distancing measures were taken. Flu transmission dropped by 44 percent in February 2020 versus the 10-15-percent drops seen in 2009 and 2017-2018 during previous flu pandemics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="FN4BST"&gt;Our study suggests that measures taken to control the spread of COVID-19 have been effective and have also had a substantial impact on influenza transmission in Hong Kong. Although the transmission dynamics and modes of transmission of COVID-19 have not been precisely elucidated, they are likely to share at least some characteristics with influenza virus transmission, because both viruses are directly transmissible respiratory pathogens with similar viral shedding dynamics.23 The measures implemented in Hong Kong are less drastic than those used to contain transmission in mainland China, and are probably more feasible in many other locations worldwide. If these measures and population responses can be sustained, avoiding fatigue among the general population, they could meaningfully mitigate the impact of a local epidemic of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="bpkysw"&gt;So social distancing — as defined by general crowd avoidance and some closures, paired with sanitary precautions — certainly appears to work, if this Hong Kong data is to be believed. The next question then is: How do countries start reopening?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="z2Png1"&gt;A gradual reopening is the best way to balance economic and health concerns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="GMpdzh"&gt;Luckily, as the public conversation about easing social distancing picks up, economists from the University of Chicago and Penn State have come out with &lt;a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w26981.pdf"&gt;a statistical model&lt;/a&gt; that tries to find an ideal balance between relaxing lockdowns to reduce the economic toll of the pandemic while also attempting to minimize the loss of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8DmP7M"&gt;It’s both a simple model (as the authors acknowledge) and also a highly technical paper, so read at your own interest. They assume there is no cure available but widespread testing is. Their conclusion is pretty straightforward: “[T]he optimal policy prescribes a lockdown starting two weeks after the outbreak, covering 60% of the population after 1 month. The lockdown is kept tight for about a full month, and is subsequently gradually withdrawn, covering 20% of the population 3 months after the initial outbreak.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XKnaHO"&gt;That’s easy enough to comprehend: To balance output and health risks, you start with a general lockdown and then gradually lighten up over a matter of months, with the most vulnerable people likely remaining in near-isolation for the longest period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AwdOkL"&gt;But it was another passage in the paper that left the biggest impression on me. The length of the lockdown, and the rate at which you relax it, depends highly on the statistical value you assign to a human life. The authors are clear that they ascribed a lower value because the people most vulnerable to dying from Covid-19 are older and have underlying health conditions. To be rigorous about these estimates, that makes some sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JBpZh4"&gt;But if you start assigning more value to those lives, then the length of the lockdown that would be desirable grows substantially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="RH3NbN"&gt;The value of the statistical life we use in our benchmark case (20 times annual GDP per capita) is on the low range of the estimates in the literature. Following Hall, Jones, and Klenow (2020), our benchmark value takes into account that the majority of the victims of the virus have a below average life expectancy. A higher value of statistical life (say 30 times annual GDP per capita), makes the abandonment of the lockdown more gradual, taking a bit more than six months to be totally abandoned. Considering a much larger value, in the order of 80 to 140 times the annual GDP per capita, implies a very strict lockdown that lasts for about 9 months, and a year after still has about 15% of the population in lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OjAwhR"&gt;This is the calculation society will be asked to make over the next year or more. How do we balance the need to relax social distancing in order to begin climbing out of an unprecedented economic crisis that has affected millions, with the inevitable surge in Covid-19 cases, and deaths, that we would expect to result?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FVL8vk"&gt;The takeaway of these two papers is clear: We must maintain certain safeguards (especially hygiene and limiting crowds), and when we start to relax some of these restrictions, we must do it gradually. We must also be nimble: Hong Kong initially sent civil servants back to work but then reverted to work-from-home protocols after its March spike. Restaurants didn’t face restrictions on their capacity in late March, when other social establishments were ordered closed for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RUSgFv"&gt;As some people have put it, the end of social distancing will not be a switch (on, then off) but a dial (more, then less, then maybe more). As Donald McNeil Jr. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/18/health/coronavirus-america-future.html"&gt;wrote for the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, after talking to more than 20 public health experts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="OmEdfJ"&gt;It was impossible to avoid gloomy forecasts for the next year. The scenario that Mr. Trump has been unrolling at his daily press briefings — that the lockdowns will end soon, that a protective pill is almost at hand, that football stadiums and restaurants will soon be full — is a fantasy, most experts said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dNuAYe"&gt;“We face a doleful future,” said Dr. Harvey V. Fineberg, a former president of the National Academy of Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="Rhs0uZ"&gt;Right now, the public is still &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19/2020/4/16/21224074/coronavirus-us-polls-lockdown-social-distancing-end"&gt;on the side of preserving social distancing&lt;/a&gt;, despite the economic costs. But we must remind ourselves, and continue to remind ourselves, that we are in this for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mrRaaX"&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story appears in VoxCare, a newsletter from Vox on the latest twists and turns in America’s health care debate. Sign up to &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/newsletters"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;get VoxCare in your inbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;along with more health care stats and news. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="iJOYn9"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21228406/coronavirus-covid-19-social-distancing-lockdown-end-research"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21228406/coronavirus-covid-19-social-distancing-lockdown-end-research</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan Scott</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T15:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T15:30:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Quarry is a slow-burn Western about guilt, racism, and salvation on the US-Mexico border</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5by32AKMG8UBxwz--_CmOSyc1DE=/0x0:5333x4000/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66680039/THEQUARRY_1.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Michael Shannon in &lt;em&gt;The Quarry.&lt;/em&gt; | Courtesy of Lionsgate&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Director Scott Teems talks about avoiding clichés and quoting the Bible in his film about dark pasts and deep prejudices.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="YCYDbu"&gt;I’ve been friends with Scott Teems for years. He’s a multitalented writer and director who’s worked in both TV (most notably as a writer on the critically acclaimed show &lt;em&gt;Rectify&lt;/em&gt;) and film. His 2009 film &lt;em&gt;That Evening Sun&lt;/em&gt;, starring Hal Holbrook, Ray McKinnon, Walton Goggins, and Mia Wasikowska, won several major prizes at its South by Southwest (SXSW) premiere. In 2014, Teems reunited with Holbrook to make &lt;em&gt;Holbrook/Twain: An American Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;, a documentary about Holbrook’s long-running one-man show in which he plays Mark Twain. Over the years, I’ve been lucky enough to have many conversations with Teems about filmmaking, the business, and how to tell a truthful story that dives into all facets of life, from human nature to religion to violence, love, and contrition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mj1sIy"&gt;Now Teems has returned with &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;, a slow-burning tale of sin and redemption, though maybe not in a way we expect it. The film centers on a mysterious man with a dark past (Shea Whigham) who arrives in a town near the US-Mexico border. The man poses as a preacher to fit into his new community&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;and soon discovers that the place contains some darkness of its own. Also starring Michael Shannon in a terrific role as the hard-bitten local sheriff, &lt;em&gt;The Quarry &lt;/em&gt;is a meditation on a lot of things — forgiveness, old hurts, racial wounds, grief — and doesn’t try to provide any easy answers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ICKyQ__r7QsY1vHPGXlJpLuBMrg=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19913474/THEQUARRY_9.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Lionsgate&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Director Scott Teems (R) with Michael Shannon on the set of &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="nDH5oc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; was slated to premiere in March at SXSW, but after the festival was canceled due to the coronavirus pandemic, the film was released digitally on April 17. I spoke to Teems, who’s currently working from his home in Los Angeles, to talk about the film, why he chose to tell this story, how he approaches the role of religion in his writing, and a lot more. Our conversation has been lightly edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="KqnVFU"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="cyUwse"&gt;How did this film come about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="wN7ROJ"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="NrceDW"&gt;After I made my first film, &lt;em&gt;That Evening Sun&lt;/em&gt;, I was looking for another project. This was 10 years ago. I came across the &lt;a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-quarry-a20d33d6-d0e0-4351-a082-f40c3378edcb/9780802141613"&gt;synopsis for [Damon Galgut’s 1995 novel &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/a&gt; somewhere online. I was immediately hooked by the premise. It had a classic set-up: stranger rolls into town, claiming to be someone he’s not. We’ve seen a bunch of stories like that, but this had a particular bent to it that grabbed me. It sort of tapped into themes that interest me greatly, namely men, violence, religion, and where those things intersect, collide, explode, crash together. That grabbed me instantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1bcND2"&gt;So I read the book. It’s set in post-apartheid South Africa, written in ‘95, so it was very different. But I felt like the hook was so universal that it could be translated to another setting, another milieu. Racial injustice and strife is not relegated to South Africa. It felt very relevant, and it’s only become more relevant in the 10 years it took to make this movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2M2aCQ"&gt;I wanted to set it in Texas because it felt like a big story with big ideas. Big ideas need a big canvas. You don’t get much bigger than Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BP9XMR"&gt;That just spoke to me, and it all kind of fell into place. I worked on the script for a while, and eventually brought my friend &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm1667551/"&gt;Andrew Brotzman&lt;/a&gt; to work on it with me [as co-writer], to help me get it to the finish line, and he’s become a great partner in this project over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="pwnPJf"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="MI6Bvh"&gt;What does the research process entail for a movie like this? It seems like there’s a lot of details to get right when you’re making a movie set in a place where cultures collide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="g9gZP0"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="k6YLgD"&gt;I’ve never been one who loves a lot of research. I was never a good student in school, so I never had great study habits. I get antsy when I’m developing a story, and I just want to write. What interests me are personal interactions, getting two people in a room with opposing points of view, or opposing desires, or one with a secret, or whatever. I like getting people in situations where there’s going to be some combustion. That’s what interests me, because that’s how I expose and explore human nature. Ultimately, what interests me in all the stories I’m telling is human nature and what does it mean to be human — all of our warts and all of our beauty and all of our terror. How each of us contain multitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8CQhZo"&gt;For me, in some ways, it was quite simple. I know a lot of people who have prejudice or who are prejudiced — myself included, even when I don’t know I am. Ultimately, to me, it’s not about studying the ways of prejudice or racism or bigotry; it’s more about studying myself and the people I’ve experienced, the times I’ve experienced that in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c4UnnA"&gt;Often racism is a much more subtle thing than what we usually see on television. Of course, those things do happen, too; we all saw Charlottesville. The history of America is riddled with very overt types of racism and prejudice. But I often see it happening more subtly. It’s a cultural blindness. You don’t even know that you’re doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ykro17"&gt;The chief [in &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;] would not claim he’s a racist. The chief would say, “What are you talking about? My two deputies over here, my best buds, they’re two Mexican guys, and my girlfriend …” But his first inclination to place blame is on the person who doesn’t look like him. The first inclination. He doesn’t even &lt;em&gt;consider&lt;/em&gt; anything else, that it might be someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4ciEf9"&gt;That’s the way it manifests, I think, in a lot of people. It’s more insidious. It’s not so overt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="A sheriff and a woman hanging laundry stand having a conversation." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/063TYJUcVkd3hsEJsHa7VwylIFg=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19913479/THEQUARRY_2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Lionsgate&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Michael Shannon and Catalina Sandino Moreno in &lt;em&gt;The Quarry.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2ql3u6"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="4hmkg3"&gt;I’ve seen a lot of movies that take place near the border between the US and Mexico that have come out in the past decade or so. A lot of them are extremely bleak. They’re trying to reinvent the Western, where there are good guys and bad guys. &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; isn’t exactly a Western, but it shares some characteristics with Western — including the stranger with a dark past who rides into town. But in contrast to some of those other movies, which lean deeply into exploring the broken, craven sides of humanity, &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; seems really interested in the people themselves as humans in search of redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="uURU04"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="cLdDI0"&gt;One thing that attracted me to this story was that it subverted the usual way these stories are told. Usually, these movies begin with the stranger rolling into town. The movie then becomes a question of &lt;em&gt;Who is he, and what has he done?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UZpYSl"&gt;What I liked about &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; was that from the beginning you know exactly what he’s done. That changes the emphasis. It changes the focus of the story, the thrust of it. It’s no longer, “Who is he and what has he done?” It’s now, “What is the cost of what he’s done, and how is that going to manifest itself upon him and everyone else throughout the story?” In &lt;em&gt;The Quarry,&lt;/em&gt; the man at the center of the story is like an Alka-Seltzer tablet dropped into the water of the town, and it just stirs up everything. He’s a catalyst for change among everyone else. He prompts reactions from everyone else — good and bad, positive and negative, and in himself as well — and then he goes through his own transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9DY5Ej"&gt;That was what interested me. It changed the focus to become much more personal. It became about the burden of guilt and conscience, the weight of conscience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="waZtfB"&gt;Certainly, when you’re making a Texas noir kind of story, you stand in the shadow of films like &lt;em&gt;No Country for Old Men&lt;/em&gt;, especially in the last decade. That was certainly an influence on me and this. I think it’s a perfect film, and it’s impossible not to be influenced by it in some respects. But ultimately, I’m just trying to tell my own story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ndnaq2"&gt;Another movie that really influenced me is &lt;em&gt;Paris, Texas&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Paris, Texas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;No Country for Old Men&lt;/em&gt; are two very different movies with very different sorts of narrative thrust. But I think there is a humanness and a warmth to &lt;em&gt;Paris, Texas&lt;/em&gt;, and a starkness to &lt;em&gt;No Country&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wvsotb"&gt;How my influences work on me is I try to soak in the things that are good, and hopefully some of that will organically pour out of me into my work. I’m not consciously trying to emulate or riff on anything, but I’m hoping that it just sort of spills out, and some goodness from those works of art that have so inspired me will somehow leak into this too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="UzDvea"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="PJmmGa"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; also made me think a lot of Cormac McCarthy’s Border trilogy, and &lt;em&gt;All the Pretty Horses &lt;/em&gt;in particular. McCarthy seems to tell stories on the border, where the Americans want to have agency and forget about the past, whereas the Mexicans know that the past is always going to shape you and catch up with you. In his stories, history is alive in Mexico. In &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;, a guy trying to get away from his past is actually confronted by it because he puts himself into a position where he’s always reading the Bible out loud to people in the church, and it tears at him. I feel like the Bible can be tricky to integrate into a movie like this without people thinking you’re trying to get preachy. Did you worry about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="kAs2Ym"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="iBDwzL"&gt;Sure. Any time religion has come into play in stuff I’ve done, most prominently in &lt;em&gt;Rectify &lt;/em&gt;— the reason [the most religious character in &lt;em&gt;Rectify&lt;/em&gt;] worked as a character was that her faith was a part of who she was. It was organic to her, and it &lt;em&gt;informed&lt;/em&gt; the story but wasn’t &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; story. It just was a part of it. It felt true to the world. There were many different voices with different beliefs that informed that character in the writers’ room. I feel like that’s the pathway toward authenticity — iron sharpens iron, and no one’s going to let your propaganda get through. Not even that it’s propaganda intentionally. Sometimes you can’t even help it when you’re just writing from who you are, and if that’s a thing you believe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yhNLy0"&gt;That’s a part of my life, certainly — religion and faith — but I’m hyperaware of how I integrate it into the stories I write. I have zero interest in any kind of propaganda. I just have such a distaste for it, so I trust that if it’s bad, it’s not gonna pass my sniff test. The last thing in the world I want to do is make something that feels trite. I actively push against that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Two men stand in a church with a cross overhead." data-mask-text="false" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/plJvVlmKTjxQPi4Hiks2Zsj7lP4=/800x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/19913484/THEQUARRY_5.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Courtesy of Lionsgate&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Shea Whigham and Michael Shannon in &lt;em&gt;The Quarry.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p id="XLD4k4"&gt;And I think that’s ultimately what &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; is trying to do: Push against your perceptions of what the Bible is or what faith is. Because if what the Bible is talking about is true, if God is real, then it’s going to stand up to any test I can throw at it. That’s what I’m interested in — banging on my belief system, banging on what I was raised on, how I was taught. What is the meaning of forgiveness? Who can be forgiven? How does that work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="l8Oo2O"&gt;I hope the end of &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt; makes people uncomfortable, because I try to address that idea head-on. But I try to do it honestly and truthfully. When you’re pretending to be a preacher, the Bible is going to be a part of it. That’s unavoidable. This idea struck me early on: If you didn’t know what you were doing, you would do the bare minimum to get by. You would do everything you could to not expose yourself as a fraud. As soon as you opened your mouth with your own opinion, if you’re pretending to be something you’re not; you’re going to expose yourself. So he just does the one thing that guarantees him not to be fraudulent, which is just to read the words on the page [of the Bible].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TCLmDd"&gt;If that is transformative or revelatory for somebody, the reader or the congregation, that’s interesting to me. Might it be also a commentary on evangelicalism in America? Perhaps. Maybe not. The cult of personality? Maybe. That’s a little bonus for me, if nothing else. But I feel like it’s authentic to the story and the world and the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="umcgGa"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="zBv179"&gt;There’s a great moment where the “preacher” reads a totally random, apocalyptic passage at a graveside and Michael Shannon’s character says, “That’s a weird fuckin’ verse.” And I mean, yeah! How many times have you wanted to say that in church?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="2Y3pfr"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="jZnVdw"&gt;I know. That’s the beauty of it. That’s the Bible. The Bible is deep and beautiful and weird as hell, and it’s okay to embrace all those elements of it, because you have to wrestle with verses like the one he reads at the funeral. That’s in there. You have to deal with it. We have to deal with it if we’re going to engage the Bible at all, and there’s nothing to be afraid of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="opya2f"&gt;So I’m just trying to call a spade and spade and say, “That’s weird. What does that mean?” It interests me. This book has stood the test of time. It’s certainly not going to be afraid of my inquiries or my attacks against it. They’re not even attacks; I’m just trying to punch holes in it and see if it stands up, because that’s my interest as a person who’s constantly trying to examine and reexamine my own relationship to it. How I feel about it today is different than how I felt about it yesterday. I’m just very, very fortunate that I’m able to do that on this scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QclA8y"&gt;I feel so grateful that this movie exists, because if I step back and look at those little details, it’s kind of a miracle that this got made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="Y6TvKy"&gt;Alissa Wilkinson&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="bBzro1"&gt;Speaking of that: This movie was supposed to premiere at South by Southwest, which was canceled. How do you feel about that? How have your hopes for the film shifted or morphed from what you were thinking a few months ago?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="f6W2Aw"&gt;Scott Teems&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p id="mIlDHq"&gt;Certainly, it’s a disappointment. I love the film festival community. I love the culture. I love the opportunity to celebrate the movie with all the people that worked on the movie. There’s such great value in the festival experience and that community. And we lost that, and we mourn for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DRQZxM"&gt;But I really believe there’s an opportunity now, with this crisis that we’re in, to offer the world a strange and suspenseful and thoughtful diversion to occupy their time. The irony is that more people will probably see this movie now than would have if we had the planned, small theatrical release, going up against a lot of bigger movies. Now those things have cleared away. We have a bit more of a path, and people at home to see it. My hope is that more people will see it. I’ve made peace with that. But it’s never going to be great that we didn’t get to show the movie at South by Southwest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="O1XEq2"&gt;I was thinking the other day about something you once said to me, when you saw [my 2014 documentary] &lt;em&gt;Holbrook/Twain&lt;/em&gt;. You said, “This is a film that grows.” When you said that, I said, “That’s what I want my movies to do.” What I took that to mean is that the movie started out a certain way and then it evolved. It went in places you didn’t expect it to, and it got bigger on a thematic level as it went along, in a surprising way. That’s what I was trying to do with &lt;em&gt;The Quarry&lt;/em&gt;, and all my movies — to start out toward a goal that you think we’re going toward, and then thematically it turns and becomes something hopefully deeper and richer. If I can accomplish that, then that’s real victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="y3srnT"&gt;The Quarry &lt;em&gt;is available from a variety of on-demand services, including &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1516588&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fitunes.apple.com%2Fus%2Fmovie%2Fthe-quarry%2Fid1504590065&amp;amp;referrer=vox.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vox.com%2Fculture%2F2020%2F4%2F20%2F21227967%2Fquarry-interview-scott-teems-michael-shannon-shea-wigham-religion" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;iTunes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Quarry-Shea-Whigham/dp/B0872CTKX9?ots=1&amp;amp;slotNum=4&amp;amp;imprToken=8ab8cc28-05ba-6b4a-11e&amp;amp;tag=curbedcom06-20&amp;amp;linkCode=w50" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amazon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/The_Quarry?id=Kyoma43jJcg.P"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Play&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Fj4WP9JbKw"&gt;&lt;em&gt;YouTube&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://go.redirectingat.com?id=66960X1516588&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vudu.com%2Fcontent%2Fmovies%2Fdetails%2FThe-Quarry-Trailer-%2F1408573&amp;amp;referrer=vox.com&amp;amp;sref=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vox.com%2Fculture%2F2020%2F4%2F20%2F21227967%2Fquarry-interview-scott-teems-michael-shannon-shea-wigham-religion" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vudu&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="5JRcfm"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/4/20/21227967/quarry-interview-scott-teems-michael-shannon-shea-wigham-religion"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/4/20/21227967/quarry-interview-scott-teems-michael-shannon-shea-wigham-religion</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alissa Wilkinson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T14:48:25-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T14:48:25-04:00</updated>
    <title>How the coronavirus outbreak is roiling the film and entertainment industries</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/9qmnMKP2fAfT_7D3lQbvxyDoUr4=/0x0:999x749/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66478877/batman.84.jpeg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Robert Pattinson in &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;, which has been subject to pandemic-related production delays. | Warner Bros.&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Most recently, Warner Bros. announced changes to release dates for movies including &lt;em&gt;The Batman, &lt;/em&gt;and San Diego Comic-Con was canceled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="BvqdKm"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19"&gt;Covid-19 coronavirus pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, which was first identified&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;in China in December, has had sweeping effects in the public health, business, and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2020/3/10/21171509/coronavirus-covid-19-airlines-lodging-cruises-chart"&gt;travel sectors&lt;/a&gt;, among others. And while the repercussions for the entertainment industry may seem to pale in comparison to the clear threat the virus poses to human life, the ripple effects do have implications for the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;people around the world who make a living producing and distributing movies, music, and more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gbvDlB"&gt;The immense and lucrative Chinese film industry &lt;a href="https://qz.com/1791867/the-coronavirus-outbreak-is-crippling-chinas-film-industry/"&gt;was hit almost immediately&lt;/a&gt; as movie theaters across the country were closed and major releases were delayed. &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/hollywood-companies-coronavirus-1203504876/"&gt;Hollywood soon began to feel the effects&lt;/a&gt;, too, and as time passes, the impact of the coronavirus on the global film and entertainment industries will certainly grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WerXVK"&gt;Consequences of the pandemic on these industries could range from lowered attendance at film festivals and disruptions in film distribution to delayed or canceled movie releases and concert dates to curtailed on-location film shoots. Financial ramifications will likely be felt by studios, filmmakers, theater owners, and more for months or even years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="GVL0zj"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"11 questions about the Covid-19 coronavirus outbreak, answered","url":"https://www.vox.com/2020/1/31/21113178/what-is-coronavirus-symptoms-travel-china-map"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Gnn8pn"&gt;Here are the biggest and most significant developments in the entertainment industry in response to the pandemic. Most recently, Warner Bros. announced new release dates for several upcoming movies, including &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;, and San Diego Comic-Con was canceled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VbJyLh"&gt;Major entertainment festival cancellations and postponements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oJ3X7d"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K-pop concerts canceled, including BTS shows: &lt;/strong&gt;On February 28, the hugely popular K-pop group &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2018/6/13/17426350/bts-history-members-explained"&gt;BTS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://time.com/5792331/bts-seoul-concerts-canceled-coronavirus/"&gt;canceled a series of concerts&lt;/a&gt; in Seoul.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The shows were&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;scheduled for April 11 and 12 and April 18 and 19 at Seoul’s Olympic Stadium. The group’s management agency said the decision was made due to the impossibility of predicting the scale of the outbreak in South Korea come April and cited the health and safety of the musicians themselves, workers, and concertgoers. Two hundred thousand fans were expected to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kMO6HL"&gt;Days earlier, BTS had asked fans to &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/entertainment-arts-51613223"&gt;avoid a series of TV appearances&lt;/a&gt; scheduled to promote their newest album, &lt;em&gt;Map Of The Soul: 7&lt;/em&gt;, which had originally been planned to include studio audiences. The group also appealed to fans via a streamed press conference. “Health is always on our minds these days, and our messages of facing your inner self and loving yourself are ultimately only possible when you’re healthy, especially since it is very risky outside these days,” one of the singers, Jimin, said. ”I hope you take care of yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jZqiWa"&gt;The entire Korean entertainment sector has been affected by the outbreak, and &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/biz/asia/k-pop-korea-showbiz-coronavirus-1203503030/"&gt;K-pop has been hit particularly hard&lt;/a&gt;, with groups including GOT7, Winner, Sechs Kies, (G) I-DLE, and others canceling scheduled tour dates. Variety &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/biz/asia/k-pop-korea-showbiz-coronavirus-1203503030/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; that box office revenue in South Korea was down 30 to 40 percent in January 2020 compared to previous years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PrlOF3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SXSW canceled: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 6, the city of Austin, Texas, declared a state of disaster, requiring the cancellation of public gatherings and events for the near future. The most notable of those is &lt;a href="http://vox.com/culture/2020/3/6/21166241/sxsw-2020-canceled-south-southwest-coronavirus"&gt;the cancellation of South by Southwest&lt;/a&gt;, the annual music, film, TV, and technology festival that serves as a significant financial powerhouse for the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJEGJP"&gt;The announcement came after a week full of major companies — including Netflix, Apple, Amazon, WarnerMedia, Facebook, Twitter, TikTok, Mashable, Intel, and more — dropping out of the well-attended event, canceling panels, premieres, and other appearances. Days later, &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/music/news/sxsw-lays-off-one-third-of-employees-in-heartbreaking-step-1203528553/"&gt;SXSW organizers&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that they had laid off&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;one-third of the festival’s employees in what they called “a necessary, but heartbreaking, step.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dacTwZ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emerald City Comic Con delayed: &lt;/strong&gt;The organizing body behind Emerald City Comic Con, the largest convention of its kind in Seattle, Washington, announced on March 6 that it&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;will &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/6/21168294/emerald-city-comic-con-canceled-postponed-coronavirus-seattle-events"&gt;postpone the event&lt;/a&gt; until sometime this summer. The event was scheduled to run from March 12 to 16. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gyENF0"&gt;“We did everything that we could to run the event as planned, but ultimately, we are following the guidance of the local public health officials indicating that conventions should now be postponed,” convention organizers Reedpop said in &lt;a href="https://www.emeraldcitycomiccon.com/About/A-Statement-From-Reedpop/?utm_source=cmv3-attendee-all&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Postponed-03-12-2020&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_term=P"&gt;a statement&lt;/a&gt; published on the Emerald City Comic Con website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KdGFYQ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cannes Film Festival delayed:&lt;/strong&gt; The 2020 edition of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2017/5/16/15508284/cannes-film-festival-2019-dates-pronounce-netflix-jury"&gt;Cannes Film Festival&lt;/a&gt;, arguably the most prestigious film festival in the world, is still in question following &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/19/21166203/cannes-2020-canceled-delayed-coronavirus-film-festival"&gt;an announcement from the festival’s organizers&lt;/a&gt; on March 19 that the gathering could be delayed until “late June or early July,” or another time. (The festival had been slated to take place May 12 to 23 and draws thousands of industries and press from around the globe each year.) The festival first &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/festivals/coronavirus-cannes-film-festival-first-case-confirmed-1203518700/"&gt;issued a statement&lt;/a&gt; on February 28 after the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/reuters/2020/02/28/world/europe/28reuters-china-health-france.html"&gt;first case of coronavirus in nearby Nice, France&lt;/a&gt;, was confirmed by the city’s mayor, saying that organizers were monitoring the situation but planned for the festival to go forward. (Cannes is a seaside resort town located on the French Riviera, about 30 km from Nice.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="X323Nq"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coachella delayed: &lt;/strong&gt;Goldenvoice, the organizers of Coachella,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;one of the largest annual music festivals in the US, announced on March 10 that &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/10/21173170/coachella-2020-dates-postponed-rescheduled-coronavirus"&gt;the festival would be postponed&lt;/a&gt; due to concerns about Covid-19. Another Goldenvoice festival, the country music-oriented Stagecoach, has also been postponed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="04N12h"&gt;The Indio, California-based event was originally set to run for two weekends, April 10-12 and April 17-19, with the same talent lineups performing both weekends. It will now run from October 9-11 and October 16-18. Stagecoach 2020 has been pushed back from April to October 23-25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AeAhkG"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronics Entertainment Expo (E3) canceled: &lt;/strong&gt;The 2020 &lt;a href="https://www.e3expo.com/"&gt;Electronic Entertainment Expo&lt;/a&gt; (E3) — the single biggest trade show in the video game industry — has been canceled. The Entertainment Software Association, which organizes the event, announced that it would not go forward with the annual event due to coronavirus fears in California, where E3 takes place. The event was scheduled for June 9 to 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TNxKf0"&gt;The organization said it will contact exhibitors and attendees about receiving full refunds for passes, and that it is considering ways to “coordinate an online experience” in lieu of the in-person event. It also maintains that E3 will return next year as planned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hnVnTn"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The NBA suspended basketball games indefinitely:&lt;/strong&gt; A player on the Utah Jazz tested positive for coronavirus on March 11, leading NBA officials to call off that night’s Jazz game just before tip-off. As a further precautionary measure, the league issued a statement that it would &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/11/21176019/nba-suspends-season-covid-19-virus"&gt;suspend the basketball season&lt;/a&gt; “until further notice.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BFoX9k"&gt;Prior to putting an early pause on the rest of the season, the NBA made other efforts to protect players and fans. The league &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/columnist/nancy-armour/2020/03/09/coronavirus-mlb-nba-nhl-mls-take-easy-way-out-media-ban/5006846002/"&gt;barred media from locker rooms&lt;/a&gt;, and publicly considered having &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/nba/story/_/id/28885303/nba-owners-leaning-playing-fans-amid-coronavirus-outbreak"&gt;teams play to empty arenas&lt;/a&gt;, before ultimately stopping play altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RQzP48"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020 Tokyo Olympics delayed: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 24, following pressure from athletes and multiple nations’ Olympic committees, the International Olympic Committee and Japanese prime minister Shinzo Abe &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/24/21185843/summer-olympics-postponed-coronavirus-tokyo-2020"&gt;announced that the 2020 Summer Olympics would be postponed&lt;/a&gt;, possibly until 2021; on March 30, &lt;a href="https://www.espn.com/olympics/story/_/id/28969950/tokyo-olympic-opening-ceremony-rescheduled-july-23-2021"&gt;the dates were set&lt;/a&gt; for July 23-August 8, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rjajEX"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Diego Comic-Con 2020 canceled&lt;/strong&gt;: On April 17, the organizers of San Diego Comic-Con announced that the yearly fan convention &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/10/21173376/coronavirus-cancel-delay-pixar-disney-mcu-broadway"&gt;will not go on as planned in 2020&lt;/a&gt;. The event will resume once again in July 2021 at the San Diego Convention Center. The cancellation marks the first time in Comic-Con’s 50-year history that the event, the largest convention of its kind in the US, will not take place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="bkApIZ"&gt;Major film release dates postponed or canceled&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="5pb37G"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warner Bros. changes release plans: &lt;/strong&gt;On April 20, Warner Bros. &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/batman-moves-back-warner-bros-date-shuffle-1290919"&gt;announced changes&lt;/a&gt; to its slate. &lt;em&gt;The Batman&lt;/em&gt;, starring Robert Pattinson, shifted from a release date of June 25, 2021, to October 1, 2021. &lt;em&gt;The Many Saints of Newark&lt;/em&gt;, a prequel to &lt;em&gt;The Sopranos&lt;/em&gt;, was delayed from September 25, 2020, to March 12, 2021. &lt;em&gt;King Richard&lt;/em&gt;, a biopic about Venus and Serena Williams’ father starring Will Smith, shifted from November 25, 2020, to November 19, 2021. An untitled Elvis movie moved from October 1, 2021 to November 5, 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HQRMpN"&gt;Two DC titles also shifted dates: &lt;em&gt;Shazam! 2&lt;/em&gt; is delayed from April 1, 2022 to November 4, 2022, and &lt;em&gt;The Flash&lt;/em&gt; moved from July 1, 2022, to June 3, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WVNZV1"&gt;So far, the studio’s release dates for Christopher Nolan’s &lt;em&gt;Tenet&lt;/em&gt; (July 17, 2020) and &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt; (August 14, 2020) remain unchanged. (&lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt; previously shifted from June to August.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HnAz5E"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Newest Pixar film delayed: &lt;/strong&gt;On April 13, Disney announced that Pixar’s latest release, &lt;em&gt;Soul&lt;/em&gt;, would open on November 20, 2020. The film was previously set to open on June 19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="GhHMuc"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Disney and Pixar’s Soul in theaters November 20, 2020. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/PixarSoul?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#PixarSoul&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/efBJuPqqj4"&gt;pic.twitter.com/efBJuPqqj4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Pixar (@Pixar) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Pixar/status/1249759604805791744?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 13, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="H15iNJ"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disney makes sweeping changes to release calendar:&lt;/strong&gt; On April 3, Disney made huge changes to its release calendar, setting dates for movies it had previously pulled without a date and moving others. &lt;em&gt;Mulan&lt;/em&gt; is now set to open on July 24, 2020, while &lt;em&gt;Jungle Cruise&lt;/em&gt;, which had been set to release that day, moved to July 30, 2021. An untitled &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones&lt;/em&gt; film moved from July 9, 2021, to July 29, 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dArNUN"&gt;Changes in the MCU calendar set off a domino effect. &lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt; is newly set for November 6, 2020, while the previous release on that date, &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi&lt;/em&gt;, shifted to May 7, 2021. Originally, &lt;em&gt;Doctor Strange 2&lt;/em&gt; was set to release on that date; it’s now set to open November 5, 2021, displacing &lt;em&gt;Thor: Love and Thunder&lt;/em&gt; until February 28, 2022. &lt;em&gt;Black Panther 2&lt;/em&gt; is still currently set for May 6, 2022, and &lt;em&gt;Captain Marvel 2&lt;/em&gt; moved from July 22 to July 8, 2022. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hlmwun"&gt;Disney also owns 20th Century Films and Searchlight Films, which had a number of changes. The Ryan Reynolds film &lt;em&gt;Free Guy&lt;/em&gt; moved from July 3 to December 11, 2020. &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt; is still set for December 18 and Ridley Scott’s &lt;em&gt;The Last Duel&lt;/em&gt; for Christmas Day. Wes Anderson’s newest film, &lt;em&gt;The French Dispatch&lt;/em&gt;, moved from July 24 to October 16, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="seBmfD"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Artemis Fowl&lt;/em&gt;, which has seen its release date pushed several times already, will be released on &lt;a href="https://disneyplus.bn5x.net/xdvoA" rel="sponsored nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Disney+&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CeO69K"&gt;Release dates for &lt;em&gt;The New Mutants&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Woman in the Window&lt;/em&gt; (originally slated for April 3 and May 15, respectively) have not been set yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V82NVw"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sony delays nearly all its movies until 2021: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 30, Sony announced that nearly all of its summer tentpole films &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/30/21200663/sony-movies-coronavirus-release-date-delays"&gt;would be delayed until late 2020 or early 2021&lt;/a&gt;. Delayed movies include Kevin Hart’s &lt;em&gt;Fatherhood&lt;/em&gt;, Jared Leto’s &lt;em&gt;Morbius&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters: Afterlife&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Uncharted&lt;/em&gt;, and the previously delayed &lt;em&gt;Peter Rabbit 2: The Runaway. &lt;/em&gt;The only film that appeared unaffected was the &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Far From Home&lt;/em&gt; sequel, which is still set for theatrical release on July 16, 2020. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="priTQW"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman 1984 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the Heights &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;releases delayed:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 24, Warner Bros. announced that it would &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/24/21191011/wonder-woman-1984-delayed-release-date-august-14"&gt;delay the release of &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984 &lt;/em&gt;from June 5 to August 14&lt;/a&gt;. The studio also pulled three films from its release schedule: &lt;em&gt;In the Heights&lt;/em&gt;, an adaptation of the Lin-Manuel Miranda musical originally scheduled for a June 26 release; &lt;em&gt;Scoob&lt;/em&gt;, a Scooby-Doo animated film originally scheduled for May 15; and &lt;em&gt;Malignant&lt;/em&gt;, a thriller from &lt;em&gt;Aquaman&lt;/em&gt; director James Wan that had originally been scheduled for August 14. (&lt;em&gt;Malignant&lt;/em&gt;’s move is designed to make room for &lt;em&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/em&gt;’s release.)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R1hTt2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NBCUniversal to release major films digitally:&lt;/strong&gt; In an unprecedented move, NBCUniversal &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/nbcuniversal-breaks-theatrical-window-will-make-movies-available-demand-immediately-1284844"&gt;announced on March 16&lt;/a&gt; that it would make some movies available digitally the same day they are released in movie theaters that remain open, including &lt;em&gt;Trolls World Tour&lt;/em&gt;, which is set to hit theaters on April 10. Movies currently in theatrical release will also be available on-demand, including &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/2/12/21133546/hunt-trailer-libs-controversy"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hunt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/2/28/21157584/invisible-man-review-elisabeth-moss-metoo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Invisible Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/2/20/21143930/emma-2020-anya-taylor-joy-autumn-de-wilde"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Movies are available for a 48-hour rental period for $19.99 in the US and an equivalent price abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Oh1Ynb"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disney postpones major releases: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 12, Disney &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/mulan-disney-delayed-coronavirus-1203532619/"&gt;confirmed&lt;/a&gt; that three of its biggest releases of the year — &lt;em&gt;Mulan&lt;/em&gt; (scheduled for March 27), &lt;em&gt;The New Mutants&lt;/em&gt; (scheduled for April 3), and &lt;em&gt;Antlers&lt;/em&gt; (scheduled for April 17) — would be postponed. &lt;em&gt;Mulan&lt;/em&gt; is now set to open on July 24, 2020. The &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2020/02/04/watch-cnbcs-full-interview-with-bob-iger-on-disneys-q4-earnings.html"&gt;Chinese&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/disney-scales-back-mulan-european-premiere-coronavirus-outbreak-1284205"&gt;European&lt;/a&gt; premieres of &lt;em&gt;Mulan&lt;/em&gt; had previously been delayed as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NvcKkr"&gt;On March 17, Disney announced the &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/box-office/black-widow-release-coronavirus-1203532996/"&gt;postponement&lt;/a&gt; of three more films: &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/17/21181940/black-widow-release-date-delay-marvel-coronavirus"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Black Widow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(originally set for May 1), &lt;em&gt;The Personal History of David Copperfield&lt;/em&gt; (May 8), and &lt;em&gt;The Woman in the Window &lt;/em&gt;(May 15). The delays followed &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/movie-theaters-close-u-s-coronavirus-1203536126/"&gt;movie theater shutdowns&lt;/a&gt; in multiple states as well as country-wide shutdowns of &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/regal-close-all-theaters-coronavirus-outbreak-1284940?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;Regal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/amc-theatres-close-all-locations-as-cinemas-us-go-dark-1285012?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;AMC&lt;/a&gt; theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="2UtuJ0"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Marvel delays the upcoming Black Widow solo film","url":"https://www.vox.com/2020/3/17/21181940/black-widow-release-date-delay-marvel-coronavirus"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="Q2mobG"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Time to Die&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;On February 16, MGM &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2020/02/no-time-to-die-chinese-premiere-canceled-coronavirus-outbreak-1202211717/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would cancel the Chinese premiere and publicity tour planned for the new James Bond movie, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/12/4/20994139/james-bond-no-time-to-die-trailer-daniel-craig"&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Time To Die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which was scheduled for April. On March 4, the studio announced that &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/bond-movie-no-time-die-delayed-postponed-due-coronavirus-1282170?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;it had delayed&lt;/a&gt; the film’s release until late November, making the film the first major tentpole release to be delayed worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YmRxj5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;On February 24, Paramount Pictures &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/02/sonic-the-hedgehog-release-date-china-coronavirus-1202867212/"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would delay the release of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/2/14/21137040/sonic-the-hedgehog-movie-review"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in China, with a new release date to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mJLHlm"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Rabbit 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;On March 10, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/peter-rabbit-2-pushed-august-coronavirus-fears-1283449?utm_source=Sailthru&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=THR%20Breaking%20News_2020-03-10%2002:00:00_gszalai&amp;amp;utm_term=hollywoodreporter_breakingnews"&gt;Sony announced&lt;/a&gt; that it would push the global&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;release of &lt;em&gt;Peter Rabbit 2: The Runaway&lt;/em&gt; from late March/early April to August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HdGFWk"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Quiet Place Part II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 12, &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place Part II&lt;/em&gt; director John Krasinski &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/johnkrasinski/status/1238115296017371137"&gt;announced via Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that the movie’s March 19 release date would be delayed. “One of the things I’m most proud of is that people have said our movie is one you have to see all together. Well due to the ever-changing circumstances of what’s going on in the world around us, now is clearly not the right time to do that,” he wrote. “As insanely excited as we are for all of you to see this movie ... I’m gonna wait to release the film till we CAN see it all together! So here’s to our group movie date! See you soon!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z7ZHWB"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast and Furious 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 12, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheFastSaga/status/1238137910756552704?s=20"&gt;Universal Pictures announced &lt;/a&gt;that it would delay the release date of the ninth installment in the &lt;em&gt;Fast and Furious&lt;/em&gt; franchise by 11 months, from May 22 to April 2, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3mzX6K"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese movies scrapped theatrical release and premiere online: &lt;/strong&gt;The biggest films of China’s year are usually&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;scheduled to release during the Lunar New Year holiday, near the end of January, but mounting fears of the coronavirus and public reticence to be in crowded spaces &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/chinese-new-year-film-releases-canceled-response-coronavirus-outbreak-1272282"&gt;caused distributors to voluntarily cancel or postpone several film releases&lt;/a&gt;. Huanxi, distributor of the Chinese blockbuster &lt;em&gt;Lost in Russia&lt;/em&gt;, announced on January 22 that the film &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/chinese-studio-release-comedy-lost-russia-online-free-coronavirus-cancellations-1272552"&gt;would premiere online&lt;/a&gt; for free. Promotional materials encouraged audiences to “stay safely at home and watch &lt;em&gt;Lost in Russia&lt;/em&gt; with your mom.” On January 31, &lt;em&gt;Enter the Fat Dragon&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/01/31/second-chinese-movie-to-premiere-online-after-virus-outbreak.html"&gt;became the second major Chinese film to premiere online&lt;/a&gt;, as theaters are closed by order of the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="putkAP"&gt;Film and TV productions halted, altered, or shut down&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="bEsqoc"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; aired remotely produced content: &lt;/strong&gt;On April 9, the producers of &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt;, which had been on hiatus since mid-March, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/all/working-remotely-saturday-night-live-air-new-content-week-n1179406"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that new, remotely produced material would air on NBC in the show’s usual Saturday night slot, 11:30 p.m. on April 11, including a “Weekend Update” segment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fcFA1z"&gt;The coronavirus has touched &lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt; in at least two ways. The show’s long-time music supervisor, Hal Willner, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/04/07/entertainment/hal-willner-dies/index.html"&gt;passed away&lt;/a&gt; on April 7 at the age of 64; he was not formally diagnosed with the virus but had consistent symptoms. And Michael Che, one of the show’s co-head writers and co-anchor with Colin Jost of “Weekend Update,” &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/michael-che-says-grandmother-died-due-coronavirus-complications-1288791"&gt;announced via social media&lt;/a&gt; on April 6 that his grandmother had passed away from coronavirus complications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZcEgZo"&gt;The show joined &lt;a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/04/late-night-shows-nyc-coronavirus.html"&gt;other late-night comedy shows&lt;/a&gt;, such as NBC’s &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show with Jimmy Fallon &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Late Night with Seth Meyers&lt;/em&gt;, CBS’s &lt;em&gt;The Late Show with Stephen Colbert&lt;/em&gt;, ABC’s &lt;em&gt;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&lt;/em&gt;, Comedy Central’s &lt;em&gt;The Daily Show&lt;/em&gt;, in creating comedy content remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b0dZA8"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eurovision canceled: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 18, the organizers of the Eurovision Song Contest &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Eurovision/status/1240267936981569538"&gt;announced via Twitter&lt;/a&gt; that the 2020 edition of the event was canceled. The event had been planned for May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OXiII9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TV shows suspend production: &lt;/strong&gt;Hundreds of shows &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/tv-productions-flux-coronavirus-concerns-1284398"&gt;have delayed or suspended production&lt;/a&gt;, including Apple’s &lt;em&gt;The Morning Show &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Little America&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/koblin/status/1238545835933208576?s=20"&gt;Netflix shows&lt;/a&gt; including &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll;&lt;/em&gt; the CW’s &lt;em&gt;Riverdale;&lt;/em&gt; NBC shows &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/coronavirus-nbcuniversal-halts-production-35-series-chicagofire-chicago-pd-chicago-med-fbi-law-order-svu-kelly-clarkson-show-angelyne-1202881992/"&gt;including&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Chicago&lt;/em&gt; dramas and &lt;em&gt;The Kelly Clarkson Show; &lt;/em&gt;CBS shows &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/coronavirus-nbcuniversal-halts-production-35-series-chicagofire-chicago-pd-chicago-med-fbi-law-order-svu-kelly-clarkson-show-angelyne-1202881992/"&gt;including&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;NCIS&lt;/em&gt; dramas, &lt;em&gt;The Amazing Race, &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Survivor;&lt;/em&gt; and many more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yXOQXK"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Saturday Night Live&lt;/em&gt; also announced on March 16 that &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/tv/news/saturday-night-live-coronavirus-1203535899/"&gt;it would suspend its next three shows&lt;/a&gt;, the first of which was scheduled for March 28, with John Krasinski hosting. (Krasinski’s film &lt;em&gt;A Quiet Place Part II&lt;/em&gt;, originally scheduled for release on March 19, was also delayed.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DVMZrV"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Late-night shows suspend production or tape without a studio audience: &lt;/strong&gt;Originally, on March 11, producers of shows including NBC’s &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show &lt;/em&gt;(hosted by Jimmy Fallon) and &lt;em&gt;Late Night&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;With Seth Meyers&lt;/em&gt;, CBS’s &lt;em&gt;Late Show&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;With Stephen Colbert&lt;/em&gt;, TBS’s &lt;em&gt;Full Frontal with Samantha Bee&lt;/em&gt;, and Comedy Central’s &lt;em&gt;Daily Show&lt;/em&gt; (hosted by Trevor Noah)&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;all&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;announced they would begin &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/tonight-show-late-show-go-live-audiences-1284071"&gt;taping without a live studio audience &lt;/a&gt;on March 16. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Dz2geS"&gt;A day later, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/business/nbc-jimmy-fallon-seth-meyers.html"&gt;NBC announced&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;Late Night&lt;/em&gt; would suspend production beginning the week of March 16; Stephen Colbert &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StephenAtHome/status/1238312113002725376?s=20"&gt;also announced&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;em&gt;Late Show &lt;/em&gt;would suspend production. All three shows were already scheduled to go into hiatus on March 23. On March 13, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/jimmy-kimmel-live-general-hospital-shut-down-production-coronavirus-1202882804/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jimmy Kimmel Live&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; also suspended production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xSrGUT"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disney suspends live-action production:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 13, Disney &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/CNBCnow/status/1238521250613547008"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that production on its live-action movies would suspend production. Affected films include &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2019/7/3/20681449/disney-live-action-little-mermaid-halle-bailey-black-ariel"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Little Mermaid&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2019/film/news/home-alone-reboot-archie-yates-ellie-kemper-rob-delaney-1203432212/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reboot, and &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/news/disney-live-action-peter-pan-peter-wendy-1203529492/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter Pan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Earlier in the day, production on Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of Ten Rings &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/shang-chi-marvel-movie-stops-production-destin-daniel-cretton-isolates-coronavirus-1202882266/"&gt;had been suspended&lt;/a&gt; due to director Destin Daniel Cretton’s decision to self-isolate upon advice of a doctor. (Marvel is owned by Disney.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k6DB23"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jia Zhangke project delayed: &lt;/strong&gt;At the Berlin Film Festival in February, famed Chinese director Jia Zhangke (&lt;em&gt;Ash Is Purest White&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;A Touch of Sin&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2020/02/coronavirus-jia-zhangke-berlin-1202212612/"&gt;told Indiewire&lt;/a&gt; that production on his new film, which was slated to begin in April, was delayed indefinitely. Jia spoke with Indiewire at the Berlin Film Festival, where his documentary &lt;em&gt;Swimming Out Till the Sea Turns Blue&lt;/em&gt; premiered. But he said that before he left, he’d feared his flight to Berlin would be canceled, and that some of his collaborators chose not to make the trip. Regarding his next film, he said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p id="BSfkjh"&gt;For some film companies and studios involved in pre-production, a lot of costs are going down the drain, and those that already started production have to be somehow cut short or suspended. Some of them are already in the process of distributing films and they’ve paid for a lot of promotion and PR costs. The economy is now taking a huge hit, and I think the investment side will be hugely impacted as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="UG30w0"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mission: Impossible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; production paused: &lt;/strong&gt;On February 26, Paramount Pictures &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/mission-impossible-vii-halts-filming-due-coronavirus-outbreak-1280821"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that it had halted a planned three-week shoot in Venice for&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;the seventh installment in the &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible&lt;/em&gt; franchise. “Out of an abundance of caution for the safety and well-being of our cast and crew, and efforts of the local Venetian government to halt public gatherings in response to the threat of coronavirus, we are altering the production plan for our three-week shoot in Venice, the scheduled first leg of an extensive production for &lt;em&gt;Mission: Impossible 7&lt;/em&gt;,”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;a Paramount spokesperson &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/heat-vision/mission-impossible-vii-halts-filming-due-coronavirus-outbreak-1280821"&gt;told the Hollywood Reporter&lt;/a&gt;. “During this hiatus we want to be mindful of the concerns of the crew and are allowing them to return home until production starts. We will continue to monitor this situation, and work alongside health and government officials as it evolves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlgEB6"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wheel of Fortune&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; tape without a studio audience: &lt;/strong&gt;Though Sony declined to comment, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/live-feed/jeopardy-wheel-fortune-film-live-audience-coronavirus-fears-1283458"&gt;sources told the Hollywood Reporter&lt;/a&gt; on March 9 that scheduled&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;tapings of the shows would go forward without a live studio audience. The measure was taken partly as a precaution for the health of &lt;em&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/em&gt; host Alex Trebek, who has stage 4 pancreatic cancer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QFQSzU"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Hanks and Rita Wilson announce they’ve contracted the virus: &lt;/strong&gt;One of Hollywood’s biggest stars, Tom Hanks, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomhanks/status/1237909897020207104?s=21"&gt;announced that&lt;/a&gt; he and his wife Rita Wilson had contracted the coronavirus while shooting Baz Luhrmann’s untitled Elvis Presley film in Australia:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="c5Bmjn"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="und" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.co/pgybgIYJdG"&gt;pic.twitter.com/pgybgIYJdG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Tom Hanks (@tomhanks) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomhanks/status/1237909897020207104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 12, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="O3zEzl"&gt;In &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/tomhanks/status/1237909897020207104?s=21"&gt;a message posted publicly on March 11&lt;/a&gt;, Hanks was his typical upbeat self:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="fp1yu2"&gt;Well, now. What to do next? The Medical Officials have protocols that must be followed. We Hanks’ will be tested, observed, and isolated for as long as public health and safety requires. Not much more to it than a one-day-at-a-time approach, no?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NdlyEk"&gt;We’ll keep the world posted and updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xs5SgQ"&gt;Take care of yourselves!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CB5VEe"&gt;Entertainment venues and attractions shut down&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="CBlndR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/3/12/21177375/disney-coronavirus-covid-19-theme-parks-disneyworld-disneyland"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disney parks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; shut down: &lt;/strong&gt;On January 25, Disney &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2020/01/24/coronavirus-in-china-shanghai-disneyland-shut-down-wuhan-virus/"&gt;shut down its Shanghai Disneyland park&lt;/a&gt; over fears of the coronavirus. The park is a major revenue generator, with 11.8 million guests in 2018, 50 percent from outside the Shanghai region, and an estimated $1 billion in annual revenue and $50 million in operating profit. A day after Shanghai Disneyland’s closure, &lt;a href="https://www.ocregister.com/2020/01/26/hong-kong-disneyland-closes-amid-chinas-coronavirus-outbreak/"&gt;Hong Kong Disneyland shut down&lt;/a&gt;. Both Disney parks in Japan closed on February 29 and Disney &lt;a href="https://www.foxnews.com/travel/coronavirus-concerns-extend-shutdown-at-tokyo-disney-resort"&gt;announced on March 11&lt;/a&gt; that they will remain closed through at least the end of April. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ah8jzX"&gt;Late in the day on March 12, Disneyland in California &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/brooksbarnesNYT/status/1238199000651591680"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; it would close the following day; by that evening, the company&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankpallotta/status/1238256920361869314"&gt; announced that all of its parks would close&lt;/a&gt;, including those in Florida and Disneyland Paris (where three staff &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/frankpallotta/status/1238256920361869314"&gt;had previously tested positive&lt;/a&gt; for coronavirus). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="agqvSw"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"Disneyland is closing amid Covid-19 fears","url":"https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2020/3/12/21177375/disney-coronavirus-covid-19-theme-parks-disneyworld-disneyland"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="NB9qRu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North American movie theaters shut down or begin “social distancing” measures: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 13, a number of theaters and theater chains, including &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/amc-theatres-coronavirus-policy-united-states-movie-theaters-box-office-1202882609/"&gt;AMC Theatres&lt;/a&gt;, and the Canadian chain &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/coronavirus-cineplex-cuts-seating-capacity-by-social-distancing-1284551?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;Cineplex&lt;/a&gt;, announced that they would be reducing the number of tickets sold to screenings by as much as 50 percent in order to enable patrons to sit further apart as part of “social distancing” measures.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="sUVv63"&gt;&lt;div data-anthem-component="readmore" data-anthem-component-data='{"stories":[{"title":"AMC will practice \"social distance\" by capping movie theater attendance at 50 percent","url":"https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/13/21179003/amc-theaters-coronavirus-movie-attendance-tickets-new-release-delays"}]}'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;&lt;p id="qjTEPR"&gt;On March 15, theaters in New York and Los Angeles &lt;a href="https://www.indiewire.com/2020/03/new-york-city-movie-theaters-coronavirus-closed-1202217827/"&gt;were shut down&lt;/a&gt; by order of their respective mayors. On March 16, Regal announced it would &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/regal-close-all-theaters-coronavirus-outbreak-1284940?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social"&gt;shut down&lt;/a&gt; all of its 543 US theaters indefinitely; later in the day, &lt;a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/amc-theatres-close-all-locations-as-cinemas-us-go-dark-1285012?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter"&gt;AMC followed suit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h3K1MR"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York City cultural sites closed: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 12, major cultural sites in New York City began to close, including &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/12/arts/design/met-museum-closing-coronavirus.html"&gt;the Metropolitan Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt;. Other institutions canceled programming for the month of March, such as &lt;a href="https://www.nypl.org/about/coronavirus"&gt;the New York Public Library&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.carnegiehall.org/Coronavirus-Information"&gt;Carnegie Hall&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lOi0cg"&gt;Within days, the Metropolitan Museum of Art &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/18/arts/design/met-museum-coronavirus-closure.html"&gt;announced that it anticipated&lt;/a&gt; staying closed through July and laying off much of its staff. On March 19, the Metropolitan Opera &lt;a href="https://www.broadwayworld.com/article/Met-Opera-Lays-Off-All-Union-Employees-Including-Musicians-and-Chorus-20200319"&gt;laid off&lt;/a&gt; all of its union employees, including musicians and chorus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Czf4la"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broadway shows closed: &lt;/strong&gt;On March 12, New York Gov. Andrew Cuomo &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jessemckinley/status/1238164693455437824"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that beginning at 5:00 pm, Broadway would be closed, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/joshbarone/status/1238165334638694401?s=20"&gt;part of a ban&lt;/a&gt; on gatherings of more than 500 people. On April 8, the Broadway League &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/08/theater/broadway-shows-canceled-june-coronavirus.html"&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that theaters would remain closed through June, and probably longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="60uXf1"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;West End closes:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 16, London’s West End shut down, following &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/pm-statement-on-coronavirus-16-march-2020"&gt;Prime Minister Boris Johnson’s speech&lt;/a&gt; urging Britons to avoid public spaces. The theaters, including the Royal Opera House, will stay closed indefinitely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0wM3pK"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Italian cultural sites closed: &lt;/strong&gt;In February, a &lt;a href="https://www.artforum.com/news/major-museums-close-as-coronavirus-cases-spike-in-northern-italy-82254"&gt;number of major museums in Venice, Milan, Turin, and other northern Italian cities were closed&lt;/a&gt; as part of the government’s aggressive attempt to contain the virus, and annual Carnivale celebrations &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-51602007"&gt;stopped early&lt;/a&gt;. By early March, with the country under complete lockdown, &lt;a href="https://www.thelocal.it/20200309/coronavirus-forces-italy-to-close-its-biggest-tourist-attractions"&gt;cultural sites across Italy were closed&lt;/a&gt;, including the Colosseum and Pompeii.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fhfI37"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese movie theaters shut down for months, tentatively begin to reopen, then re-close: &lt;/strong&gt;Hoping to contain the coronavirus outbreak, on January 23 the Chinese government &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/asia/coronavirus-china-theaters-outbreak-1203478152/"&gt;temporarily shut down movie theaters&lt;/a&gt; throughout the country until further notice. A total&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/01/china-coronavirus-high-profile-film-productions-shut-down-quarantines-1202845124/"&gt;film production shutdown&lt;/a&gt; soon followed. Loss of revenue over the Lunar New Year holiday in late January, during which movie theaters typically see an uptick in ticket sales, amounted to a staggering $1 billion, &lt;a href="https://fortune.com/2020/02/07/china-hollywood-movie-market-coronavirus/"&gt;according to analysts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jOtzNk"&gt;By March 23, about &lt;a href="https://variety.com/2020/film/asia/cinemas-china-reopen-coronavirus-recedes-1203542000/"&gt;500 cinemas had reopened in China&lt;/a&gt;, roughly 5 percent of the cinemas in the country that were open before the outbreak. &lt;em&gt;Variety&lt;/em&gt; reported that box office earnings remained minimal. But by March 27, &lt;a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/china-orders-re-closing-all-cinemas-nationwide-1202894103/"&gt;they were closed again&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DPo82T"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese cultural attractions closed: &lt;/strong&gt;Other cultural attractions and institutions in China that have been closed to the public&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;include Tiananmen Square’s National Museum of China, the Forbidden City, and a section of the Great Wall of China located near Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jp4i2D"&gt;&lt;em&gt;We will continue to update this article as the story develops.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/10/21173376/coronavirus-cancel-delay-pixar-disney-batman-dc"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/culture/2020/3/10/21173376/coronavirus-cancel-delay-pixar-disney-batman-dc</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alissa Wilkinson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T14:06:39-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T14:06:39-04:00</updated>
    <title>What we know about a mass shooting in Nova Scotia, Canada</title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="Four officers, in olive fatigues, body armor, and helmets, stand with their hands on their rifles." src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/B5EZZod1LeLyj5KWNkiKttFclHo=/0x0:3000x2250/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66675717/GettyImages_1210404346.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Members of the Royal Canadian Mounted Police at the gas station in Enfield, Nova Scotia, where the suspect was apprehended. | Tim Krochak/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Police say at least 18 people were killed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="z2LM2c"&gt;A shooter killed at least &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/7c9a33ae52420e0ddbfb5275898a7e79"&gt;18 people&lt;/a&gt; across Nova Scotia, Canada, police said Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xmliYK"&gt;The suspect, a 51-year-old man, died shortly after being apprehended in Enfield, Nova Scotia, a town about 20 miles north of Halifax. Police believe he was responsible for a series of shootings that began in Portapique — a small town about 60 miles north of Halifax — around 10:30 pm local time Saturday night. As of Monday, officials said they were conducting investigations at 16 sites across Nova Scotia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cXmBcN"&gt;For at least a few hours on Sunday morning, the suspect was disguised as a police officer. Officials aren’t yet sure of his motive, but Royal Canadian Mounted Police Chief Superintendent Chris Leather said Sunday the fact that “this individual had a uniform and a police car at his disposal certainly speaks to it not being a random act.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGNZw2"&gt;The suspect was ultimately apprehended at an Enfield gas station Sunday morning, after having switched vehicles. He was killed about 12 hours after police in Portapique first received a complaint about “a person with firearms” Saturday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NbX0Jq"&gt;Mass shootings are rare in Canada, particularly compared with the United States, in large part because stringent gun laws were enacted after a 1989 shooting that left 14 people dead. Now, any Canadian wishing to own a gun must register the firearm and undergo training, a risk assessment, and a background check. It’s not yet clear whether the suspect’s weapon was registered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3PKtkn"&gt;Monday, politicians faced a number of questions about new gun control legislation. In response, Canadian Minister of Public Safety Bill Blair promised that Parliament will bring forward new gun control legislation “as quickly as possible” once it returns from a &lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/politics/parties-negotiate-terms-of-parliaments-return-1.5537696"&gt;coronavirus-related recess&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xuy2zn"&gt;The story is still developing. Here’s what we know, and don’t know, so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3bR0xA"&gt;What we know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="fkoKin"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/04/19/police-officer-dead-another-injured-in-canada-shooting/"&gt;Royal Canadian Mounted Police Chief Superintendent Chris Leather&lt;/a&gt; said on Monday said that at least &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/7c9a33ae52420e0ddbfb5275898a7e79"&gt;18 people&lt;/a&gt; were killed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OahGRl"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/nova-scotia/mass-killing-shooting-victims-remembered-1.5538032"&gt;The victims include&lt;/a&gt;: a 23-year veteran of the police force; a teacher at Debert Elementary School; two members of the Victorian Order of Nurses; a family of three living in Portapique; a couple living about 30 miles north of Portapique; and a man who lived near the couple, in West Wentworth, who is believed to have died trying to help his neighbors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="UKrBM4"&gt;At least one other officer was shot and wounded. He &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/homenews/news/493621-16-people-killed-in-canadas-deadliest-mass-shooting"&gt;was hospitalized&lt;/a&gt;; officials said Monday he is currently “recovering” at home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="4GwnD8"&gt;Police said the suspect knew some of his victims, while others seemed to be targeted at random.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="DdLo6m"&gt;The shooting began Saturday night; &lt;a href="https://www.canberratimes.com.au/story/6727908/at-least-10-dead-in-canada-shooting/?cs=14232"&gt;police in Portapique, Nova Scotia&lt;/a&gt;, received a call about “a person with firearms” at 10:30 pm ADT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="QFNzQw"&gt;On Monday, the RCMP said it was investigating at least five fires, including of homes and vehicles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="zNb0Yh"&gt;The suspect &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RCMPNS/status/1251862523357335552?s=20"&gt;impersonated a police officer&lt;/a&gt; for a time early Sunday and was in possession of what first appeared to be an RCMP vehicle. However, the RCMP stressed on Twitter that the suspect was &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RCMPNS/status/1251882212397637634?s=20"&gt;not a member of the mounted police&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AhGhm4"&gt;The RCMP caught up to the suspect, identified as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RCMPNS/status/1251841546862952453?s=20"&gt;51-year-old Gabriel Wortman&lt;/a&gt; of both Halifax and Portapique, at a gas station in Enfield, Nova Scotia. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tBXYvU"&gt;The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RCMPNS/status/1251883308763447296?s=20"&gt;suspect was killed&lt;/a&gt; after an &lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/canadian-authorities-say-mass-shooting-suspect-may-have-been-disguised-n1187381?cid=sm_npd_nn_fb_ma"&gt;exchange of gunfire&lt;/a&gt; around 10:40 am ADT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="AnyTrP"&gt;On Sunday, Nova Scotia Premier &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/7c9a33ae52420e0ddbfb5275898a7e79"&gt;Stephen McNeil&lt;/a&gt; called the shooting “one of the most senseless acts of violence in our province’s history,” and lamented it causing an additional “heavy burden” on a community already concerned about the coronavirus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="wiHehk"&gt;A number of other leaders also expressed condolences. &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/7c9a33ae52420e0ddbfb5275898a7e79"&gt;Prime Minister Justin Trudeau&lt;/a&gt; said, “My heart goes out to everyone affected in what is a terrible situation.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="XMDB8z"&gt;Leather said Monday that the RCMP is investigating at least 16 crime scenes across Nova Scotia, and expects the police investigation to continue “for months to come.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0gFvo7"&gt;What we don’t know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="Kw9AT5"&gt;The shooter’s motive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tqRqCA"&gt;The firearm, or firearms, used by the shooter, and whether he had registered weapons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ucJHfi"&gt;How many people were killed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="ruRVdb"&gt;How many people were wounded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="kysHEG"&gt;The identities of all of the victims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="iJOYn9"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LXv99J"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B6tkJ9"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/world/2020/4/19/21227349/mass-shooting-nova-scotia-canada-enfield-portapique"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/world/2020/4/19/21227349/mass-shooting-nova-scotia-canada-enfield-portapique</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sean Collins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T13:50:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T13:50:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Congress is close to a deal on a roughly $450 billion small-business funding bill </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/T8o4Vupc6M-Rq9kqMAuz3HnYRfs=/543x0:4887x3258/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66679121/1216234787.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;House Speaker Nancy Pelosi is interviewed by CNN about the US government’s response to the ongoing global coronavirus pandemic in the rotunda of the Russell Senate Office Building on Capitol Hill, April 1, 2020, in Washington, DC.&amp;nbsp; | Chip Somodevilla/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It focuses primary on small-business loans but includes money for hospitals and testing as well. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="psk320"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/16/21223637/paycheck-protection-program-funding"&gt;After a critical small-business loans program ran out of money&lt;/a&gt; last Thursday, the pressure has been on for Congress — &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/9/21214800/senate-democrats-block-small-business-funding-paycheck-protection-program"&gt;and Democrats in particular&lt;/a&gt; —&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;to end a weeks-long impasse and approve more funding for it. In the coming days, lawmakers may be set to do just that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7WrXlA"&gt;Democrats and Republicans this weekend indicated that they were close to a deal on what they’re calling an “interim” spending bill that’s intended to give small-business loan programs — including the Paycheck Protection Program and the Economic Injury Disaster Loan program — a major boost. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VlBHPZ"&gt;“We have common ground,” House Speaker Nancy Pelosi said &lt;a href="https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/week-transcript-19-20-house-speaker-nancy-pelosi/story?id=70229816"&gt;during an appearance on ABC’s &lt;em&gt;This Week&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. “I think we’re very close to agreement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wvQhI0"&gt;The latest legislation, which follows the $2 trillion CARES Act stimulus that lawmakers approved in March, is focused primarily on small businesses, many of which have been hit especially hard by the coronavirus pandemic’s economic fallout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cZEsbS"&gt;Although the stimulus included in the CARES Act already allocated $360 billion for new small-business loans, that money was depleted in a matter of weeks. While more than 1.6 million small businesses have obtained PPP loans so far, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/marcorubio/status/1251476502589431810"&gt;hundreds of thousands of others &lt;/a&gt;have seen their applications sit in limbo simply because the programs are out of money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5GMkDo"&gt;Congress’s latest bill is poised to include roughly $450 billion in funding, including about $350 billion to replenish the small-business loan programs, $75 billion for hospitals, and $25 billion for testing, according to Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin. The exact figures for the deal are still being negotiated along with the specifics regarding how the funding for testing would be doled out, &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/04/19/politics/small-business-funding-congress-mnuchin-schumer-cnntv/index.html"&gt;CNN reports&lt;/a&gt; — so there could be some characteristic delays in actually getting it passed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZhGcQn"&gt;If lawmakers can reach an agreement soon, the House and Senate are set to pass it swiftly this week — though procedural opposition in the lower chamber could mean that at least half of the House’s members would have to return for an in-person vote. (If just one Congress member opposes the deal, that person can call for a quorum and roll-call vote, which would require the majority of the House to be present.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4k0L7j"&gt;This interim package is expected to precede another massive stimulus bill, which Congress is slated to work on in the coming months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="r5ZsHk"&gt;What the “interim” spending package includes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vQ9Ju1"&gt;The interim spending package reflects a compromise between Democrats and Republicans, who’ve been at an impasse over this bill for more than two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n8yAgZ"&gt;While the two parties broadly agree on the need to allocate more funding for small businesses, &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/9/21214800/senate-democrats-block-small-business-funding-paycheck-protection-program"&gt;Democrats have focused on using the leverage&lt;/a&gt; they have to push Republicans to consider a more generous spending package that would address shortfalls that hospitals, states, and cities are experiencing as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uogKLx"&gt;This tactic has been successful, in part. The anticipated spending deal is more expansive than the original Republican proposal; that was limited to $250 billion in funding for the Paycheck Protection Program, which provides forgivable grants to businesses and nonprofits. The newer version also includes about $50 billion for the Economic Injury Disaster Loan program, which has emergency grants that can expedite relief for these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="BBDwDf"&gt;Additionally, the deal contains $75 billion for hospitals, which have been overwhelmed by the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/3/17/21183263/coronavirus-us-hospitals-elective-surgeries-icu-masks"&gt;simultaneous costs of preparing for the coronavirus&lt;/a&gt; and the revenue declines that have resulted as elective procedures are postponed. Another $25 billion is intended to help ramp up the country’s testing capacity, a development that experts view as vital to determining when to reopen the economy more fully. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7vYEA9"&gt;The main Democratic demand that has been omitted from this deal is the additional funding that lawmakers would like to see go to cities and states — many of which are facing &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2020/4/16/21223398/state-city-budgets-coronavirus-economic-crisis-ppp-cares-act"&gt;incredible financial strain given reductions in tax revenue&lt;/a&gt; and a surge in costs to combat the coronavirus. Mnuchin signaled that this issue would be addressed as part of negotiations for the next funding bill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CwwSFj"&gt;“The president has heard from the governors and he’s prepared to discuss that in the next bill,” Mnuchin said during an appearance on CNN’s &lt;em&gt;State of the Union. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dzYq45"&gt;Trump’s reluctance to consider state funding in the current bill is the result of a couple of factors, &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/newsletters/playbook/2020/04/19/wh-testing-isnt-the-real-issue-488929"&gt;according to Politico&lt;/a&gt;. Among them: The administration is concerned that it would have less leverage over the states regarding when they reopen their economies if they had more funding to help them weather this period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NpdvuR"&gt;This bill is not anticipated to address an expansion in SNAP (food stamp) benefits and hazard pay for front-line workers, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="IxIJaC"&gt;What’s next &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="5L3IGo"&gt;Lawmakers are continuing negotiations on the specifics of this “interim” spending deal, with the goal of announcing the final version later on Monday or Tuesday. Once they do, both the Senate and the House intend to take it up in rapid succession. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dLmHSJ"&gt;The majority of members in both chambers are working remotely and not physically present at the Capitol, which could pose a procedural challenge later this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SirrdW"&gt;When votes were taking place on the CARES package in March, for example, Rep. Thomas Massie (R-KY) demanded a quorum — or a majority of the House — be present for the vote. It is possible that Massie or another member might make the same request again, meaning some members would have to travel back to the Capitol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="e0JlpQ"&gt;Pelosi has also said that the House could consider the use of proxy voting for future bills, if members continue to work remotely during the pandemic. Were members to move forward with this approach, the House would have to vote on a rule to approve proxy voting. Like the name suggests, proxy voting enables members to allow someone who’s physically present in the House chamber to vote on their behalf, so not everyone would have to travel back to Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C59lpA"&gt;Given the scale of the economic impact that workers and businesses have seen so far, the next package could potentially surpass the first CARES Act in cost and size. Democrats and some Republicans are pushing for the consideration of more ambitious proposals, including for the government to cover &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/17/21225177/senate-paycheck-security-act"&gt;a portion of payrolls for companies&lt;/a&gt; that have been affected by the economic crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8KLuX0"&gt;“This is a time for all of us to be creative,” &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/17/21225177/senate-paycheck-security-act"&gt;Sen. Mark Warner (D-VA) recently told Vox&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21227868/paycheck-protection-program-congress-small-business-funding"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21227868/paycheck-protection-program-congress-small-business-funding</id>
    <author>
      <name>Li Zhou</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2020-04-20T13:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-04-20T13:40:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Lockdown protests, Congress nears another stimulus deal: Monday’s coronavirus news </title>
    <content type="html">  
    &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xs6n2DyHTFirKi-6Aq-N2yDFzws=/58x0:4666x3456/1310x983/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/66679071/1210404370.jpg.0.jpg" /&gt;

  &lt;small&gt;Matt Marshall of the right-wing group Washington State Three Percent speaks at a ‘Hazardous Liberty! Defend the Constitution!’ rally to protest the stay-at-home order, at the Capitol building on April 19 in Olympia, Washington. | Karen Ducey/Getty Images&lt;/small&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here’s what you need to know today.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="6mbZaX"&gt;Worldwide, the number of &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19"&gt;coronavirus&lt;/a&gt; cases topped 2.4 million. The United States accounts for nearly 762,000 of those recorded infections, as of April 20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AK4unE"&gt;The United States is very much still in the middle of a public health crisis, yet the pain of the pandemic &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/04/19/nyc-coronavirus-cases-reach-nearly-130000-death-toll-at-8811/"&gt;is not spread equally across the country&lt;/a&gt;. That’s why protesters in some states are beginning to agitate against the lockdown restrictions that have slowed the spread of the outbreak but have also suffocated the economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vk7EeL"&gt;Protesters in &lt;a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2020/04/protests-washington-colorado-coronavirus-curbs-200420030414300.html"&gt;Colorado&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.kxan.com/news/coronavirus/protesters-pressure-texas-government-to-reopen-state-as-coronavirus-death-toll-grows/"&gt;Texas&lt;/a&gt;, and elsewhere are demanding the government reopen schools and businesses in their states, even though public health officials say doing so too soon risks a surge of infections and that &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/apr/20/fauci-coronavirus-covid-19-stay-home"&gt;any rollback must be gradual&lt;/a&gt;. Even though &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/coronavirus-covid19/2020/4/19/21226922/coronavirus-stay-home-protests-texas-maryland-indiana-utah-new-hampshire"&gt;recent polling&lt;/a&gt; has shown that a majority of Americans fear what might happen if stay-at-home orders are lifted too soon, the fault lines are growing deeper, with some of the tumult being &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/04/19/pence-defends-trump-tweets-194753"&gt;fomented by the president himself&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F1napA"&gt;Experts say that any plans to reopen will need to include large-scale testing and contact tracing, along with ways to show who has been infected by the disease and whether they’ve gained any immunity. &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/in-depth/news/2020/04/20/coronavirus-testing-how-antibody-tests-work-and-why-needed/2988440001/"&gt;Antibody tests&lt;/a&gt; are starting to be rolled out, but questions &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/19/us/coronavirus-antibody-tests.html"&gt;remain about their accuracy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.cnn.com/videos/health/2020/04/16/covid-19-antibody-testing-fda-griffin-dnt-lead-vpx.cnn"&gt;availability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QLYH1b"&gt;But a little more economic relief may be on the way as Congress and the White House near another stimulus package, which will include hundreds of billions more for small businesses. The small-business assistance passed in the first coronavirus stimulus bill has &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/16/21223637/paycheck-protection-program-funding"&gt;already run out of money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="H8X7BH"&gt;Here’s what you need to know today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="fcZznl"&gt;Protests over the shutdown grew louder over the weekend &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="7GUaad"&gt;Maybe nothing sums up the current moment quite like these photographs from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/McclaranAlyson"&gt;Alyson McClaran&lt;/a&gt;, a photojournalist in Denver, Colorado, of health care workers in surgical masks and scrubs standing in the middle of city streets to block people — many in cars — who came out to protest against the stay-at-home measures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="CZEQGt"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Health care workers stand in the street in counter-protest to hundreds of people who gathered at the State Capitol to demand the stay-at-home order be lifted in Denver, Colo., on Sunday, April 19, 2020. Photos by Alyson McClaran &lt;a href="https://t.co/yanunDrVKj"&gt;pic.twitter.com/yanunDrVKj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Alyson McClaran (@McclaranAlyson) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/McclaranAlyson/status/1252043676445839361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 20, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="BVXrr4"&gt;Demonstrators across the country — from &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/protest-planned-to-reopen-maryland-death-toll-rises-in-region-amid-coronavirus-pandemic/2020/04/18/d3b743bc-817a-11ea-a3ee-13e1ae0a3571_story.html"&gt;Maryland&lt;/a&gt; to&lt;a href="https://www.wave3.com/2020/04/19/residents-against-indiana-stay-at-home-order-protest-outside-governors-mansion/"&gt; Indiana&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/video/us/politics/100000007095297/austin-texas-protest-stay-at-home-coronavirus.html"&gt;Texas&lt;/a&gt; — gathered outside state capitols over the weekend in defiance of lockdown restrictions. They’re angry about the shutdown measures that have upended the US economy, shuttering businesses and leaving at least &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2020/04/16/unemployment-claims-coronavirus/"&gt;22 million people&lt;/a&gt; unemployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rV6A96"&gt;These protesters are still a minority, organized largely by &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2020/apr/18/coronavirus-americans-protest-stay-at-home"&gt;right-wing and anti-government activist groups&lt;/a&gt;. But they’re an increasingly vocal and visible minority, with echoes of the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/19/21225195/stay-at-home-protests-trump-tea-party-reelection"&gt;early days of the Tea Party&lt;/a&gt;. And they are being egged on by President Donald Trump, who tweeted last week about &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/17/21225134/trump-liberate-tweets-minnesota-virginia-michigan-coronavirus-fox-news"&gt;“liberating”&lt;/a&gt; states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HDJqq5"&gt;Rolling out the &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/17/21224866/coronavirus-update-trump-china-wuhan-bolsonaro-mandetta"&gt;federal government’s new guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for how to gradually reopen some parts of the country, Trump said he would ultimately defer to governors on when it was safe to open up. Yet his tweets seem to contradict that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1ZpXdY"&gt;Public health officials in his own administration have said that attempting to lift stay-at-home measures too quickly could cause coronavirus cases to spike once again. Dr. Anthony Fauci, the nation’s top infectious disease expert, told &lt;em&gt;Good Morning America&lt;/em&gt; Sunday that, unless the US gets the virus under control, “the real recovery economically is not gonna happen.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYdKwZ"&gt;“So what you do if you jump the gun, and go into a situation where you have a big spike, you’re going to set yourself back,” &lt;a href="https://www.newsweek.com/dr-fauci-says-easing-lockdown-measures-too-soon-will-lead-big-spike-coronavirus-cases-its-1498944"&gt;Fauci said&lt;/a&gt;. “So as painful as it is to go by the careful guidelines of gradually phasing into a reopening, it’s gonna backfire [if you don’t].”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tw272D"&gt;Right now, most Americans agree, according to a recent poll by the &lt;a href="https://www.people-press.org/2020/04/16/most-americans-say-trump-was-too-slow-in-initial-response-to-coronavirus-threat/?utm_source=AdaptiveMailer&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20-04-16%20COVID%20Trump_GEN%20DISTRO&amp;amp;org=982&amp;amp;lvl=100&amp;amp;ite=5984&amp;amp;lea=1332873&amp;amp;ctr=0&amp;amp;par=1&amp;amp;trk="&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7I39jZ"&gt;Some countries, including Germany, have begun to ease their lockdown restrictions, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/germany-to-begin-gradually-reopening-its-economy-next-week-11586989014"&gt;but they’re taking baby steps&lt;/a&gt;: allowing some businesses to reopen with limits on the number of customers allowed in and everyone still expected to follow all other social-distancing restrictions.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Bars are still closed, and big gatherings are still banned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Xa7CwB"&gt;Does the US have the capacity to open up?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="FlgO4W"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/19/us/coronavirus-updates.html"&gt;Governors&lt;/a&gt; and public health &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2020/04/17/us/coronavirus-testing-states.html"&gt;experts&lt;/a&gt; say that taking even tentative steps toward reopening will require greater testing capacity — more than double or &lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/amp/news/2020/04/07/former-fda-chiefs-outline-plan-to-reopen-the-economy-when-broad-testing-in-place-171344"&gt;triple&lt;/a&gt; what the US is doing now. One study conducted by a panel of experts at Harvard estimated that the US must be able to complete 5 million tests a day by early June and 20 million tests per day by late July to “&lt;a href="https://ethics.harvard.edu/Covid-Roadmap"&gt;fully mobilize the economy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ZBD9k"&gt;The US is currently conducting about 150,000 tests per day, &lt;a href="https://covidtracking.com/data/us-daily"&gt;according to the COVID Tracking Project&lt;/a&gt;, for a population of about 330 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cKdvq0"&gt;The Trump administration has said states &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1252260074782887941?s=20"&gt;must shoulder the testing burden&lt;/a&gt;. But governors have resisted, saying the lack of coordination across the country and states’ lack of resources are making that an impossible task to achieve. States need things like swabs and reagents to conduct the tests, which rely on manufacturers and supply chains. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IRFbNp"&gt;“It’s not accurate to say there’s plenty of testing out there, and the governors should just get it done,” &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/19/trump-to-use-defense-production-act-to-increase-swab-production-amid-coronavirus-testing-shortage.html"&gt;Maryland Gov. Larry Hogan ​said​ on &lt;em&gt;State of the Union​&lt;/em&gt; Sunday&lt;/a&gt;.​ “That’s just not being straightforward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DWj36X"&gt;Hogan &lt;a href="https://baltimore.cbslocal.com/2020/04/20/maryland-acquires-500k-covid-19-tests-from-labs-in-south-korea-after-gov-hogan-first-lady-yumi-hogan-close-deal/"&gt;announced a deal&lt;/a&gt; with suppliers in South Korea to import 500,000 tests to Maryland. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/20/us/coronavirus-updates.html#link-1cebc986"&gt;Per the New York Times,&lt;/a&gt; he was able to secure the deal in large part thanks to his wife, “a Korean immigrant who speaks fluent Korean, had been on the phone in the middle of the night helping to secure the final deal with two labs to sell Maryland the tests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="vfVdoi"&gt;Trump has said &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/19/trump-to-use-defense-production-act-to-increase-swab-production-amid-coronavirus-testing-shortage.html"&gt;he will use the Defense Production Act&lt;/a&gt; to increase swab production by 20 million per month (&lt;a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2020/04/19/trump-dpa-testing-swabs-reported-shortages-195721"&gt;though these shortages are nothing new&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g0FseX"&gt;And beyond testing for new infections, the US still needs a better grasp on who might have recovered from the virus. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/3/30/21186822/immunity-to-covid-19-test-coronavirus-rt-pcr-antibody"&gt;Serological tests&lt;/a&gt;, which test for antibodies, might help gather this information and show who has gained some immunity. This may allow some people to return to the workforce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r7B2wE"&gt;There are still a lot of questions about the coronavirus, including whether and for how long it might confer immunity, but there’s hope these antibody tests can help piece together this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="n7sW32"&gt;And serological tests are starting to become available: &lt;a href="https://nypost.com/2020/04/19/new-york-to-begin-coronavirus-antibody-testing-survey-on-monday/"&gt;New York&lt;/a&gt; is beginning to test antibodies this week from a 3,000-person sample. But there are a lot of questions about &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/19/us/coronavirus-antibody-tests.html"&gt;their accuracy and efficacy&lt;/a&gt;. The Food and Drug Administration has issued emergency use authorization to just four tests, but there are some 90 tests now on the market that haven’t had prior review, according &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2020/04/19/fda-antibody-tests-coronavirus-review/"&gt;to the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t2ktyf"&gt;Some critics are saying that it’s now such a free-for-all that it could be even more dangerous if the tests don’t work or offer false results, leading people to believe they have some immunity if they do not. This is especially worrisome if states are relying on these results to determine whether and how to lift lockdowns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="81Axia"&gt;The FDA and other government agencies are now trying to vet the tests, but the risks are real. Just look at the United Kingdom, which paid $20 million for at-home antibody kits from China. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/16/world/europe/coronavirus-antibody-test-uk.html"&gt;They didn’t work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="znKYCc"&gt;Congress gets close to passing another stimulus deal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="DWkSoG"&gt;Last week, the Paycheck Protection Program &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/16/21223637/paycheck-protection-program-funding"&gt;ran out of money&lt;/a&gt;. The program, which earmarked $349 billion for small businesses, was included in the $2 trillion coronavirus stimulus passed in March. The initiative offers loans to businesses that are forgivable if the businesses maintain their payrolls and essential expenses. But with so many businesses shut down, demand for the program has exceeded the funds available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fuD7Sx"&gt;Congress wants to give the initiative much more cash, but Republicans and Democrats have been at odds over what to include in this latest round of stimulus. There are signs the two sides are coming close to an agreement on &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/us-policy/2020/04/19/trump-coronavirus-democrats-small-business/"&gt;an approximately $450 billion package&lt;/a&gt;. It will include about $300 billion in additional money for the Paycheck Protection Program, some of which will be set aside for minority- and veteran-owned and rural businesses. The bill will also include an additional $60 billion for another emergency loan program, another $75 billion to assist hospitals, and $25 billion to expand testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4cbhgI"&gt;Both Democrats and Republicans agree that the small business loan program needs a refresher, but Democrats had held out for more money for hospitals, testing, and for states and local governments &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/12/state-and-local-governments-face-budget-crunch-hurting-hopes-for-a-quick-economic-recovery.html"&gt;that are having to cut their budgets&lt;/a&gt; after the expense of battling the coronavirus. Right now, it appears as though the Democrats got the GOP to budge on hospitals, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/pelosi-says-we-re-close-to-deal-on-small-business-funding-11587301707"&gt;but the states may have to wait for the next stimulus package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="hYB9Cs"&gt;And some good news&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="zjpmpT"&gt;Captain Tom Moore is turning 100 years old at the end of April. To celebrate his centennial, the war veteran walked 100 laps in his garden to raise money for the United Kingdom’s National Health Service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cBl7FD"&gt;Moore, who lives in Bedfordshire, England, originally wanted to raise £1,000 ($1,200). In the end, he raised more than &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-britain-veteran/british-veteran-raises-22-million-by-walking-for-the-health-service-idUSKBN21Z0PJ"&gt;£20 million&lt;/a&gt; — that is, about $25 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yZbtqs"&gt;“The sun will shine on you again and the clouds will go away,” he told reporters, &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-health-coronavirus-britain-veteran/british-veteran-raises-22-million-by-walking-for-the-health-service-idUSKBN21Z0PJ"&gt;referring to the coronavirus crisis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="6iSkBr"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;He's done it!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Captain Tom Moore, a 99-year-old war veteran who is walking 100 laps of his garden before his 100th birthday to raise money for the NHS, has completed his challenge!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;He has raised more than £12m for the health service&lt;a href="https://t.co/eUiQiX5AAP"&gt;https://t.co/eUiQiX5AAP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/T4WOWCAqOk"&gt;pic.twitter.com/T4WOWCAqOk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— BBC News (UK) (@BBCNews) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BBCNews/status/1250691140514390016?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 16, 2020&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="p-entry-hr" id="iJOYn9"&gt;
&lt;p id="DdEUmD"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Vox’s explanatory journalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RBRwjt"&gt;Every day at Vox, we aim to answer your most important questions and provide you, and our audience around the world, with information that has the power to save lives. Our mission has never been more vital than it is in this moment: to empower you through understanding. Vox’s work is reaching more people than ever, but our distinctive brand of explanatory journalism takes resources — particularly during a pandemic and an economic downturn. Your financial contribution will not constitute a donation, but it will enable our staff to continue to offer free articles, videos, and podcasts at the quality and volume that this moment requires. &lt;a href="https://www.vox.com/pages/support-now"&gt;Please consider making a contribution to Vox today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21227840/coronavirus-updates-protests-testing-congress-stimulus"/>
    <id>https://www.vox.com/2020/4/20/21227840/coronavirus-updates-protests-testing-congress-stimulus</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jen Kirby</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
